[
  {
    "questionNum": 71001,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Two Lives “?",
    "answerText": " Vikram Seth"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71002,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Sthrihridayam”?",
    "answerText": " Balamani Amma"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71003,
    "questionText": " The Currency of Chile?",
    "answerText": " Peso"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71004,
    "questionText": " Who was the author of the Malayalam novel Indulekha?",
    "answerText": " O Chandu Menon"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71005,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Vinaya Patrika ?",
    "answerText": " Thulasi Das"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71006,
    "questionText": " The Euro was introduced to world financial markets as an accounting currency on?",
    "answerText": " 1st January 1999"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71007,
    "questionText": " The process by which leaves excretes water through stomata is called ?",
    "answerText": " transpiration process"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71008,
    "questionText": " Which is the birth place of Ayyankali?",
    "answerText": " Venganoor"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71009,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of We Need to Talk about Kevin?",
    "answerText": " Lionel Shriver"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71010,
    "questionText": " Which operation was the continuation of operation Desert storm?",
    "answerText": " 'Operation Desert Fox'"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71011,
    "questionText": " Exophthalmic goitre is also known as?",
    "answerText": " Grave's disease."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71012,
    "questionText": " The Currency of Finland?",
    "answerText": " Mark"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71013,
    "questionText": " The world’s Second Earth Summit (2002) was at?",
    "answerText": " Johannesburg (South Africa)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71014,
    "questionText": " The main function of the liver is to produce?",
    "answerText": " Bile"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71015,
    "questionText": " On the death of Vasco Da Gama on 29 December 1524; where was dead body cremated?",
    "answerText": " St. Francis Church at Fort Cochin."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71016,
    "questionText": " Cholera causing bacteria is ?",
    "answerText": " Vibrio Cholerae"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71017,
    "questionText": " Deficiency of Vitamin B1 (Thiamine) causes?",
    "answerText": " Beri Beri"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71018,
    "questionText": " Plant systematics is the study of ?",
    "answerText": " Classification and naming of plants"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71019,
    "questionText": " Punic Wars were fought between Rome and ?",
    "answerText": " Carthage"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71020,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Krishnakavithakal”?",
    "answerText": " Sugathakumari"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71021,
    "questionText": " Which is the first Ecotourism project in India?",
    "answerText": " Thenmala"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71022,
    "questionText": " Central Institute of Medicinal and Aromatic Plants is located at?",
    "answerText": " Lucknow (Uttar Pradesh)."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71023,
    "questionText": " The district through which large number of rivers flow?",
    "answerText": " Kasargod"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71024,
    "questionText": " Nepal celebrated its first day as a republic on ?",
    "answerText": " 28-May-08"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71025,
    "questionText": " റിസർവ് ബാങ്ക് സാമ്പത്തിക കാര്യങ്ങളിൽ മേൽനോട്ടം വഹിക്കാത്ത സംസ്ഥാനം? ",
    "answerText": " ജമ്മുകാശ്മീർ "
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71026,
    "questionText": " Who introduced Islam in Kerala around 644 AD?",
    "answerText": " Malik Bin Dinar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71027,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of India from Curzon to Nehru and After ?",
    "answerText": " Durga Das"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71028,
    "questionText": " Kerala Bhasha Institute wass established on?",
    "answerText": " 11-Mar-68"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71029,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “What Went Wrong ... and continues”?",
    "answerText": " Kiran Bedi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71030,
    "questionText": " Most Beautiful Memorial?",
    "answerText": " Taj Mahal (Agra)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71031,
    "questionText": " Kanpur is on the bank of which River?",
    "answerText": " Ganges"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71032,
    "questionText": " Largest and Longest bone in a man ?",
    "answerText": " Femur (thigh bone)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71033,
    "questionText": " Duleep Trophy is associated with?",
    "answerText": " Cricket"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71034,
    "questionText": " The biggest crisis of the early stage of Cold War was the Berlin Blockade which began in ?",
    "answerText": 1948
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71035,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Manasantharam”?",
    "answerText": " Balachandran Chullikkadu"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71036,
    "questionText": " Who was the chief diety of people during the Sangham Age?",
    "answerText": " Kottavai (a form of Durga (war goddess)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71037,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Nicholas Nickelby”?",
    "answerText": " Charles Dickens"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71038,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Sultry Days”?",
    "answerText": " Shobha De"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71039,
    "questionText": " Well known tourist centre Thekkadi is in?",
    "answerText": " Idukki district"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71040,
    "questionText": " Who was the last of Kulasekaharas of Mahodayapuram?",
    "answerText": " Ramavarma Kulasekhara"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71041,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Old Curiosity Shop”?",
    "answerText": " Charles Dickens"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71042,
    "questionText": " Small Island where Columbus landed in 1492?",
    "answerText": " Wattlings Island"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71043,
    "questionText": " The Capital of Togo?",
    "answerText": " Lome"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71044,
    "questionText": " Which is the official currency of the European Union (EU) ?",
    "answerText": " Euro"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71045,
    "questionText": " Fishes respire through ?",
    "answerText": " Gills"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71046,
    "questionText": " Cattle Breading research institute is located in?",
    "answerText": " Hissar (Haryana)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71047,
    "questionText": " What was the name of the Atom bomb dropped in Hiroshima?",
    "answerText": " 'Little boy"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71048,
    "questionText": " Vietnam’s freedom struggle was led by?",
    "answerText": " Ho Chimin"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71049,
    "questionText": " World's first test tube baby Louie Brown was born on?",
    "answerText": " 25th July 1978"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71050,
    "questionText": " Homer; the blind poet; lived in the ?",
    "answerText": " 9th century BC"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71051,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of The Ambassadors ?",
    "answerText": " Henry James"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71052,
    "questionText": " Who was the director of ‘Balan’, the first talkie in malayalam?",
    "answerText": " S Nottani"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71053,
    "questionText": " The Currency of Albania?",
    "answerText": " Lek"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71054,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Sreekrishna Karnamritham. “?",
    "answerText": " Poonthanam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71055,
    "questionText": " The shortest bone in the human body is ?",
    "answerText": " Stapes in middle ear"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71056,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Man Who Changed China”?",
    "answerText": " Pearl S. Buck"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71057,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Persuasion”?",
    "answerText": " Jane Austen"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71058,
    "questionText": " The Longest Play?",
    "answerText": " The Mouse-Trap (Agatha Christie’s Novel)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71059,
    "questionText": " The Capital of India?",
    "answerText": " New Delhi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71060,
    "questionText": " The amount of air moving in and out of lungs during each breath is called?",
    "answerText": " Tidal volume"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71061,
    "questionText": " Vitamin C is also called?",
    "answerText": " Ascorbic Acid"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71062,
    "questionText": " Where is the only cantonment in Kerala located?",
    "answerText": " Kannur"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71063,
    "questionText": " Which writer received Jnanapith Award in 1984”?",
    "answerText": " Thakazhi Siva Sankara Pillai"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71064,
    "questionText": " Greeks were collectively known as?",
    "answerText": " Hellenes"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71065,
    "questionText": " Jerusalem Synagogue built by King Solomon was destructed in 587 BC by ?",
    "answerText": " Nebukanisar; The Babilonian king"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71066,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Dwandhayudham “?",
    "answerText": " Malayattoor Ramakrishnan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71067,
    "questionText": " Whch is the world's most ferocious fresh water fish?",
    "answerText": " Piranha"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71068,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Prathama Pratishruti”?",
    "answerText": " Ashapurna Devi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71069,
    "questionText": " Princess Diana was killed in a car accident in?",
    "answerText": " Paris on 31 August 1997"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71070,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Apple Cart”?",
    "answerText": " G.B.Shaw"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71071,
    "questionText": " Which city is the 100% urbanised city in the world?",
    "answerText": " Singapore"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71072,
    "questionText": " The concept of rolling plan was accepted in?",
    "answerText": 1977
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71073,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “The Bells”?",
    "answerText": " Edgar Allen Poe."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71074,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of Hydrogen?",
    "answerText": " Henry Cavendish"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71075,
    "questionText": " Mamography test is used to diagnose?",
    "answerText": " Breast Cancer"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71076,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of Kala-a-zar Fever?",
    "answerText": " U.N.Bramachari"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71077,
    "questionText": " On which date Nehru Trophy Boat race is held in Punnarnada backwaters in Alappuzha?",
    "answerText": " Second Saturday of August every year"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71078,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Viswarupam”?",
    "answerText": " Lalitham bika Antharjenam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71079,
    "questionText": " The central control of respiratory activity in human body is exercised by?",
    "answerText": " Medulla Oblongata"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71080,
    "questionText": " Pollination between two flowers of one plant",
    "answerText": " Gytanogamy"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71081,
    "questionText": " Largest Natural Harbour (India)?",
    "answerText": " Visakhapatnam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71082,
    "questionText": " Jetayu Para, a giant rock, is located at?",
    "answerText": " Chadayamangalam (Kollam)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71083,
    "questionText": " The Royal symbol of Chera's was ?",
    "answerText": " Tiger"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71084,
    "questionText": " Isaac Newton was born in England in ?",
    "answerText": 1642
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71085,
    "questionText": " Dark Continent?",
    "answerText": " Africa"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71086,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Robe”?",
    "answerText": " The L.C. Douglas"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71087,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Uncle Tom's Cabin?",
    "answerText": " Harriet Beecher Stowe"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71088,
    "questionText": " Don Juan",
    "answerText": " Lord Byron"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71089,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Days of His Grace?",
    "answerText": " Eyvind Johnson"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71090,
    "questionText": " Hitler and his wife Iva Brown committed suicide in?",
    "answerText": " 30-Apr-45"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71091,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Viswambhara”?",
    "answerText": " Dr.C.N.Reddy"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71092,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Tamerlaine the Great”?",
    "answerText": " Marlows Christopher"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71093,
    "questionText": " The writings of ancient Rome are classified as ?",
    "answerText": " Latin Literature"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71094,
    "questionText": " Political organisations which originated in Europe after the First World War were collectively known as?",
    "answerText": " Fascist Movements"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71095,
    "questionText": " The largest blood vessel in the body is?",
    "answerText": " Aorta"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71096,
    "questionText": " What is correcting errors in a program is called?",
    "answerText": " Debugging"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71097,
    "questionText": " Smallest Union Territory in Population?",
    "answerText": " Lakshadweep (India)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71098,
    "questionText": " Which Diwan of Travancore started Postal Savings Scheme 1947?",
    "answerText": " Diwan Raghva Iyer"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71099,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of The Pick up ?",
    "answerText": " Nadine Gordimer"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71100,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Oedipus the King”?",
    "answerText": " Sophocles"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71101,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “In the company of women lave Truth and a little Malice”?",
    "answerText": " Khushwant Singh"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71102,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Beyond Peace”?",
    "answerText": " Richard Nixon"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71103,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Viswadarshanam”?",
    "answerText": " G. Sankara Kurup"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71104,
    "questionText": " The organ in the body which accumulates iodine is ?",
    "answerText": " Thyroid gland"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71105,
    "questionText": " The Treaty of VersaiIle's resulted in the foundation of ?",
    "answerText": " League of Nations in 1919"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71106,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Greater Common Good”?",
    "answerText": " Arundhati Roy"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71107,
    "questionText": " Who is the greatest of the Greek dramatists; who wrote famous tragedies?",
    "answerText": " Aesceles"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71108,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Uppu”?",
    "answerText": " O.N.V Kurup"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71109,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “La Divina Comedia”?",
    "answerText": " A Dante"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71110,
    "questionText": " Central Salt and Marine Chemical Research Institute is located at?",
    "answerText": " Bhavnagar (Gujarat)."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71111,
    "questionText": " First Chief Minister of Kerala who lost power through article 356 of Indian Constitution is?",
    "answerText": " E.M.S. Namboothiripad."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71112,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Who is known as the Poet of the Bhakthi movement”?",
    "answerText": " Poonthanam (15th century)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71113,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Invisible Man?",
    "answerText": " H.G Wells"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71114,
    "questionText": " Pollination by water?",
    "answerText": " Hydrophily"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71115,
    "questionText": " Which canal connects the Pacific and Atlantic Oceans?",
    "answerText": " Panama Canal"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71116,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Social Contract”?",
    "answerText": " Rousseau"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71117,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Beyond Boundaries ?",
    "answerText": " Swaraj Paul"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71118,
    "questionText": " Data that is copied from an application is stored in the ?",
    "answerText": " Clipboard"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71119,
    "questionText": " Hyderabad is on the bank of which River?",
    "answerText": " Musi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71120,
    "questionText": " Who is considered as the father of the Jews?",
    "answerText": " Abraham"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71121,
    "questionText": " Physical Quality of Life Index (PQLI) was undertaken by ?",
    "answerText": " Morris in 1980s"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71122,
    "questionText": " Which is the official publication of Kerala Sports Council?",
    "answerText": " 'Kayikavedi'"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71123,
    "questionText": " Which Governor General gave him the name Raja Kesava Das?",
    "answerText": " Lord Mornington (Lord Wellesley)."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71124,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “And Quiet Flows the Don”?",
    "answerText": " Mikhail Sholokov"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71125,
    "questionText": " Highest Railway Bridge?",
    "answerText": " Fades Bridge on river Sioule 144 m long and 132.5 m above the river. (Clermont Ferrand; rance)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71126,
    "questionText": " American Stock exchange Index is known as ?",
    "answerText": " NASDAQ "
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71127,
    "questionText": " Greek poet who wrote poems in honour of victorious athletes?",
    "answerText": " Pindar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71128,
    "questionText": " Who compiled the first Malayalam Dictionary?",
    "answerText": " Herman Gundert (1814-1893)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71129,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of The Brave New World?",
    "answerText": " Aldous Huxley"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71130,
    "questionText": " Who was the last military officer of the American revolution to become the President of America?",
    "answerText": " James Munroe"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71131,
    "questionText": " First popular ministry of Travancore headed by ?",
    "answerText": " Pattom A. Thanu Pillai on March 24; 1948."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71132,
    "questionText": " Who was the second foreigner to receive the Bharat Ratna?",
    "answerText": " Nelson Mandela"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71133,
    "questionText": " Hundred Years War (1337-1453) was fought between?",
    "answerText": " England and France"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71134,
    "questionText": " Headquarters of ADB is at?",
    "answerText": " Manila in Philippines"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71135,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Men from Stone Age to Clone Age”?",
    "answerText": " Bob Beale"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71136,
    "questionText": " Famous tourist spot 'Panchalikkulam' is in?",
    "answerText": " Idukki district"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71137,
    "questionText": " The Capital of Lesotho?",
    "answerText": " Maseru"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71138,
    "questionText": " Hamburg is on the bank of which River?",
    "answerText": " Elbe"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71139,
    "questionText": " Biggest State (India)?",
    "answerText": " Madhya Pradesh"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71140,
    "questionText": " G.V. Raja Memorial Trophy is associated with?",
    "answerText": " Football"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71141,
    "questionText": " Who modified the Old Calendar which had only 355 days; and introduced a New Calendar ?",
    "answerText": " Julius Caesar (Julian Calendar)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71142,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Death and After”?",
    "answerText": " Just. Y.R. Krishna lyer"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71143,
    "questionText": " Who were the traditional naval commanders of Calicut Zamorin?",
    "answerText": " Kunjali Marakkars"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71144,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Dynamics of Social Change”?",
    "answerText": " Chandra Shekar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71145,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Curtain Raisers”?",
    "answerText": " Natwar Singh"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71146,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Chistable”?",
    "answerText": " Samuel Taylor Coleridge"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71147,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of D.D.T.?",
    "answerText": " D. Paul Muller"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71148,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Towards Total Revolution”?",
    "answerText": " J a y a p r a k a s h Narayan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71149,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Nineteen Eighty Four?",
    "answerText": " George Orwell"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71150,
    "questionText": " The Capital of Guatemala?",
    "answerText": " Guatemala City"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71151,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ We Indians”?",
    "answerText": " Khushwant Singh"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71152,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Mati Mahal”?",
    "answerText": " Gopinath Mohanty"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71153,
    "questionText": " Who is known as Maiden Queen ?",
    "answerText": " Elizabeth I"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71154,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Kanya Vanangal”?",
    "answerText": " Punathil KunjabdulJah"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71155,
    "questionText": " Jules Rimet Trophy is associated with?",
    "answerText": " World Soccer Cup"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71156,
    "questionText": " A currency the exchange value of which is expected to remain stable due to strong performance by it in an economy is called?",
    "answerText": " Hard currency"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71157,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of ‘Nana’?",
    "answerText": " Emile Zola"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71158,
    "questionText": " National Institute of Communicable Diseases is located in ?",
    "answerText": " Delhi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71159,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “If l am Assassinated”?",
    "answerText": " ZA. Bhutto"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71160,
    "questionText": " The number of chambers in the heart of reptiles is ?",
    "answerText": " Three."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71161,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of Film (Musical)?",
    "answerText": " Lee de Forest"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71162,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of Safety Lamp?",
    "answerText": " Humphrey Davy"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71163,
    "questionText": " Name the economy in which public enterprise or state ownership of capital exists in all the important spheres of productive activity?",
    "answerText": " Socialist Economy"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71164,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Farm House”?",
    "answerText": " George Orwell"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71165,
    "questionText": " Indira Gandhi Rashtriya Urban academic is located at?",
    "answerText": " Rai Bareli (Uttar Pradesh)."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71166,
    "questionText": " Founder of Comintang Party?",
    "answerText": " Dr.Sunyat Sen"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71167,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “The Scarlet Letter”?",
    "answerText": " Nathaniel Hawthorne"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71168,
    "questionText": " The Capital of Angola?",
    "answerText": " Luanda"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71169,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “New Dimensions of India s Foreign Policy”?",
    "answerText": " Atal Behari Vajpayee"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71170,
    "questionText": " Who wrote Centuries ?",
    "answerText": " Nostradamus"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71171,
    "questionText": " The Capital of Hungary?",
    "answerText": " Budapest"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71172,
    "questionText": " Who is the creator of the famous character Sydney Carton?",
    "answerText": " Charles Dickens"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71173,
    "questionText": " 'Madona' and 'The School of Athens' are the famous paintings of ?",
    "answerText": " Raphael"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71174,
    "questionText": " One of the most important results of the First World War was the Great Depression which started in?",
    "answerText": " USA in 1929"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71175,
    "questionText": " Name the only vein carrying pure blood?",
    "answerText": " Pulmonary vein"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71176,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Brick Lane”?",
    "answerText": " Monica Ali"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71177,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Kashmir A Tragedy of Errors”?",
    "answerText": " Tavleen Singh"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71178,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Moby Dick?",
    "answerText": " Herman Melville"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71179,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of My Struggle ?",
    "answerText": " E:K.Nayanar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71180,
    "questionText": " Vitamin A; D; E;K are fat soluble whereas vitamin B complex and C are ?",
    "answerText": " Water soluble."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71181,
    "questionText": " Who was the first Speaker of Kerala Legislative Assembly of Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Shankara Narayanan Thampi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71182,
    "questionText": " World Computer literacy day is celebrated on ?",
    "answerText": " 2-Dec-16"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71183,
    "questionText": " Egyptian civilisation flourished on the banks of ?",
    "answerText": " Nile river"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71184,
    "questionText": " If the face value of the money is greater than the intrinsic value of the money; it is termed as?",
    "answerText": " Fiat Money"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71185,
    "questionText": " Who were the parents of Sree Narayana Guru?",
    "answerText": " Madanasan and Kuttiyamma"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71186,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of India in Slow Motion ?",
    "answerText": " Mark Tully"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71187,
    "questionText": " Todd Memorial Trophy is associated with?",
    "answerText": " Football"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71188,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Lost Child”?",
    "answerText": " Mulk Raj Anand"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71189,
    "questionText": " Name the Travancore king who attacked Thekkumkur and destroyed the palace and the Thaliyil Fort?",
    "answerText": " Marthanda Varma"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71190,
    "questionText": " Who wrote Jatimeemamsa'?",
    "answerText": " Sree Narayana Guru"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71191,
    "questionText": " The black granite idol of Lord Buddha known as Karumadikuttan is found at?",
    "answerText": " Ambalapuzha"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71192,
    "questionText": " MAN stands for ?",
    "answerText": " Metropolitan Area Network"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71193,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of Motion; Law of?",
    "answerText": " Newton"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71194,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Pathumayude Aadu”?",
    "answerText": " Vaikom Muhammed Basheer"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71195,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Manvini Bhavai”?",
    "answerText": " Pannalal Patel"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71196,
    "questionText": " Neolithic Age also known as ?",
    "answerText": " New Stone Age"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71197,
    "questionText": " First American President who was ousted from his party while in Office ?",
    "answerText": " John Tailor"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71198,
    "questionText": " iago; Macbeth; Jessica",
    "answerText": " Shakespeare"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71199,
    "questionText": " Delhi is on the bank of which River?",
    "answerText": " Yamuna"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71200,
    "questionText": " Who was the first to become Central Cabinet Minister after becoming Chief Minister?",
    "answerText": " A.K.Antony"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71201,
    "questionText": " The US decision to intervene in the ……….may be considered as formally ushering in-of the Cold War?",
    "answerText": " Greek Civil War"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71202,
    "questionText": " Workshop of Europe?",
    "answerText": " Belgium"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71203,
    "questionText": " First Indian to win Nobel Prize?",
    "answerText": " Dr. Rabindranath Tagore"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71204,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “The Day in Shadow”?",
    "answerText": " Nayantara Sehgal"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71205,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Sense and Sensibility ?",
    "answerText": " Jane Austen"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71206,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “The Pickwick Papers”?",
    "answerText": " Charles Dickens"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71207,
    "questionText": " Character",
    "answerText": " Creator"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71208,
    "questionText": " Air Defence and Guided Missiles School is located at?",
    "answerText": " Gopalpur (Orissa)."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71209,
    "questionText": " E.E.G (Electro Encephalogram) is used to record changes in the electric potential in various areas of?",
    "answerText": " Brain"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71210,
    "questionText": " The scientific name of Crow is?",
    "answerText": " Corvus Splendens"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71211,
    "questionText": " Longest Railway Route?",
    "answerText": " Himsagar Express"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71212,
    "questionText": " Early Middle Ages is also known as?",
    "answerText": " 'Dark Ages'"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71213,
    "questionText": " With which sport Chakkola Trophy is associated?",
    "answerText": " Football"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71214,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Detective ?",
    "answerText": " Arthur Hailey"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71215,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Parakumbol”?",
    "answerText": " Madhavikutty (Kamala Surayya)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71216,
    "questionText": " The Capital of Uruguay?",
    "answerText": " Montivideo"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71217,
    "questionText": " Cairo is on the bank of which River?",
    "answerText": " Nile"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71218,
    "questionText": " Capital of Libya is?",
    "answerText": " Tripoli"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71219,
    "questionText": " The scientific name of Rubber is?",
    "answerText": " Hevea brasiliensis"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71220,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “The serpent and the Rope”?",
    "answerText": " Raja Rao"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71221,
    "questionText": " Who was the first person to identify the models of aeroplanes; submarines and cars ?",
    "answerText": " Leonardo Da Vinci"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71222,
    "questionText": " Oxygen starvation due to low atmospheric oxygen is called ?",
    "answerText": " asphyxia."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71223,
    "questionText": " Vijayawada is on the bank of which River?",
    "answerText": " Krishna"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71224,
    "questionText": " In which year Sree Narayana Guru performed the famous Aruvippuram Consecration (Siva)?",
    "answerText": 1888
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71225,
    "questionText": " Shakespeare was born in ?",
    "answerText": " AD 1564 and died in AD 1616."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71226,
    "questionText": " Birbal Sahni Institute of Palaecobotany is located at?",
    "answerText": " Lucknow (Uttar Pradesh)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71227,
    "questionText": " Stock exchange Index of Tokyo is?",
    "answerText": " Nikkei"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71228,
    "questionText": " The London Mission Society (LMS) at Nagercoil was established in 1816 under the patronage of?",
    "answerText": " Gauri Parvati Bai."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71229,
    "questionText": " The Greeco- Persian conflict began during the period of?",
    "answerText": " Darius I"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71230,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of India in the New Millennium?",
    "answerText": " P.E. Alexander"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71231,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “IlIiad”?",
    "answerText": " Homer"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71232,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Choice of techniques”?",
    "answerText": " Dr Amartya Sen"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71233,
    "questionText": " The Soviet German Non Aggression Pact was signed on ?",
    "answerText": " 23-Aug-39"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71234,
    "questionText": " Who is the founder of Facebook?",
    "answerText": " Mark Zukerberg"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71235,
    "questionText": " As a result of the first Opium War the Chinese province of Hong Kong came under the control of Britain in?",
    "answerText": 1844
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71236,
    "questionText": " ‘Natural demise of capitalism’ was predicted by?",
    "answerText": " Joseph Schumpeter"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71237,
    "questionText": " Which is the brain of the computer?",
    "answerText": " CPU"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71238,
    "questionText": " The Capital of Kiribati?",
    "answerText": " Tarawa"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71239,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Super Power ?",
    "answerText": " Raghav Bahd"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71240,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of Shorthand?",
    "answerText": " Pitman"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71241,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Ranga Bhoomi”?",
    "answerText": " Prem Chand"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71242,
    "questionText": " Travancore Timber Products is located at?",
    "answerText": " Kottayam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71243,
    "questionText": " Largest City in Population (World)?",
    "answerText": " Shangai (China)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71244,
    "questionText": " The rebellion led by the peasants of Keniya against the British?",
    "answerText": " Mau-Mau Rebellion"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71245,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Othello ?",
    "answerText": " William Shakespeare"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71246,
    "questionText": " Which American President is known as 'Human Chain' ?",
    "answerText": " Benjamin Harrison"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71247,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “The Road Ahead”?",
    "answerText": " Bill Gates"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71248,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Dilemma of Our Time ?",
    "answerText": " Harold Joseph Laski"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71249,
    "questionText": " Name the only one European country which was not affected by great depression was?",
    "answerText": " Russia"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71250,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “History of the Congress Party”?",
    "answerText": " Dr Shankar Ghose"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71251,
    "questionText": " Queen of the Adriatic?",
    "answerText": " Venice"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71252,
    "questionText": " From which century Aryans began to dominate Kerala?",
    "answerText": " 4th Century"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71253,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Chiriyum Chinthayum”?",
    "answerText": " E.Y.Krishana Pillai"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71254,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Price of Power”?",
    "answerText": " Seymour Hersh"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71255,
    "questionText": " The leucocytes that are able to produce the anticoagulant heparin are?",
    "answerText": " Basophils"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71256,
    "questionText": " Peddling Prosperity was written by ?",
    "answerText": " Paul Krugman"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71257,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Karana Booshanam”?",
    "answerText": " Uloor S Parameshwara Iyer"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71258,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Time Machine ?",
    "answerText": " H.G. Wells"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71259,
    "questionText": " Shortest Day?",
    "answerText": " December 22 (in N o r t h e r n Hemisphere)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71260,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Velichathil”?",
    "answerText": " Balamani Amma"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71261,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Imaging India”?",
    "answerText": " Nandan Nilekani"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71262,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Wuthering Heights?",
    "answerText": " Emily Bronte"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71263,
    "questionText": " First conference of the Kerala Pradesh Congress Committee(K.P.C.C.) was held on?",
    "answerText": " 23 April 1921."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71264,
    "questionText": " The Capital of Cambodia?",
    "answerText": " Phnom-Penh"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71265,
    "questionText": " The Currency of Syria?",
    "answerText": " Syrian Pound Dinar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71266,
    "questionText": " Stock exchange Index of Brazil is?",
    "answerText": " Bove spa"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71267,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “The Lotus Eaters”?",
    "answerText": " Alfred Tennyson"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71268,
    "questionText": " Kerala Simham' is a historical novel written Pazhassi Raja by ?",
    "answerText": " Sardar K.M. Panicker"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71269,
    "questionText": " Murugappa Gold Cup is associated with?",
    "answerText": " Hockey"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71270,
    "questionText": " Dengue fever is spread by?",
    "answerText": " Aedes aegypti mosquitoes."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71271,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of From Surprise to Victory ?",
    "answerText": " Gen. V.P. Malik"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71272,
    "questionText": " Which organ of the body is affected by Bright's disease?",
    "answerText": " Kidney"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71273,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “India in Slow Motion”?",
    "answerText": " Mark Tully"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71274,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Seven summers”?",
    "answerText": " Mulk Raj Anand"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71275,
    "questionText": " Name computer literacy programme launched in Malappuram District in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Akshaya Project"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71276,
    "questionText": " Who started ‘Mitavadi magazine’ from Tellicherry in 1907?",
    "answerText": " Moorkoth Kumaran"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71277,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Pakistan Crisis ?",
    "answerText": " David Loshak"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71278,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “I am not an island”?",
    "answerText": " K.A.Abbas"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71279,
    "questionText": " Kunchan Memorial is situated in?",
    "answerText": " Lakkidi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71280,
    "questionText": " Presbiopia; a disease of the eye; also known as age sightness Can be removed by ?",
    "answerText": " Bifocal Lens"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71281,
    "questionText": " The normal blood pressure of a healthy adult is?",
    "answerText": " 120/180 mm/Hg."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71282,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of Beriberi (cause)?",
    "answerText": " Eijkman"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71283,
    "questionText": " Which see animal shows parantal care?",
    "answerText": " Hippocampus (sea horse)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71284,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Human Factor?",
    "answerText": " Graham Greene"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71285,
    "questionText": " In Travancore who introduced the direct management of Devaswams by Government ?",
    "answerText": " Col. Monro."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71286,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Oruthulli Velicham”?",
    "answerText": " O.N.V Kurup"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71287,
    "questionText": " Which place is known as the Bermingham of Central Africa?",
    "answerText": " Sinja – Trophus"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71288,
    "questionText": " Which was the first known Kathaprasangham?",
    "answerText": " Markhandeya Charitham performed by Sathyadevan in the model of Harikatha"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71289,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “To the Lighthouse”?",
    "answerText": " Virginia Woolf"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71290,
    "questionText": " Who were the two leaders of reformation in Switzerland?",
    "answerText": " Ulrich Zwingli and John Calvin"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71291,
    "questionText": " The Electricity Agitation Which agitation was organised in Cochi against the privitization of Electricity supply in Cochin Town?",
    "answerText": " Diwan R.K. Shanmukham Chetti"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71292,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Doctor's Dilemma”?",
    "answerText": " George Bernard Shaw"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71293,
    "questionText": " Which country is known as the 'Britain of the East'?",
    "answerText": " Japan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71294,
    "questionText": " Who was the founder of Kerala Deepika, the first malayalam paper published from Malabar?",
    "answerText": " Chengulathu Kunhirama Menon"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71295,
    "questionText": " Which district is known as Migrants District?",
    "answerText": " Idukki"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71296,
    "questionText": " Florence Chadwik is associated with which Sport?",
    "answerText": " Skiing"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71297,
    "questionText": " The heartbeat of a child is around?",
    "answerText": " l40/min"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71298,
    "questionText": " Panama got the Panama Canal from US in?",
    "answerText": 1999
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71299,
    "questionText": " City of Quiet thoroughfares?",
    "answerText": " Venice"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71300,
    "questionText": " Rowing Training Centre in Kerala was founded at?",
    "answerText": " Alappuzha in 1987"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71301,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of The Snows of Kilimanjaro?",
    "answerText": " Earnest Hemingway."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71302,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Life and Times”?",
    "answerText": " V.V.Giri"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71303,
    "questionText": " How many countries are members of OPEC?",
    "answerText": 11
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71304,
    "questionText": " Biopsy test is used to diagnose?",
    "answerText": " Cancer"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71305,
    "questionText": " Who is considered as the founder of Judaism?",
    "answerText": " Mosses"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71306,
    "questionText": " Fatty acids and glycerol are absorbed into …..?",
    "answerText": " Lymph"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71307,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Murder in the Cathedral”?",
    "answerText": " T.S. Eliot"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71308,
    "questionText": " The total number fear bones are ?",
    "answerText": " Six."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71309,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Pair of Blue Eyes ?",
    "answerText": " Thomas Hardy"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71310,
    "questionText": " First American President who was subjected to impeachment is ?",
    "answerText": " John Tailor"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71311,
    "questionText": " To which race 92% of the Chinese people belong?",
    "answerText": " The Han race"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71312,
    "questionText": " Who is the creator of the famous characters Antonio; Ariel; Bassanio;?",
    "answerText": " Shakespeare"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71313,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Law Verses Justice”?",
    "answerText": " V.R. Krishna Iyer"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71314,
    "questionText": " Which district is known as the granary of Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Palakkad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71315,
    "questionText": " Glycocelated Haemoglobin test is used to diagnose?",
    "answerText": " Diabetics"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71316,
    "questionText": " Land of Setting Sun?",
    "answerText": " United Kingdom"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71317,
    "questionText": " Who was the first editor of Malayalam Manorama?",
    "answerText": " Kandathil Varghese Mappilai"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71318,
    "questionText": " Who is known as II Duke ?",
    "answerText": " Mussolini"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71319,
    "questionText": " Patna is on the bank of which River?",
    "answerText": " Ganges"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71320,
    "questionText": " Romanoff Emperors were known as ?",
    "answerText": " Czars."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71321,
    "questionText": " The Bill of Rights was accepted in England after the Glorious Revolution in ?",
    "answerText": 1689
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71322,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Beauty and Revolution “?",
    "answerText": " K.A.Abbas"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71323,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “The Shadow Lines”?",
    "answerText": " Amitav Ghosh"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71324,
    "questionText": " Odyssey relates to the adventures of the Greek hero ?",
    "answerText": " Odysseus or Ulysses."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71325,
    "questionText": " City of Flowers?",
    "answerText": " Cape Town (S.Africa)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71326,
    "questionText": " The Currency of Ghana?",
    "answerText": " Cedi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71327,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Aachanum Makalum”?",
    "answerText": " Vallathol Narayana Menon"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71328,
    "questionText": " In which we can find Banasurankotta in ?",
    "answerText": " Wynadu"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71329,
    "questionText": " The loss of elasticity of muscles results in a disease called?",
    "answerText": " Parkinson's disease"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71330,
    "questionText": " Father of Taxonomy?",
    "answerText": " Carolus Linnaeus"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71331,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “The Guide; ”?",
    "answerText": " R.K.Narayan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71332,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of Spectacles?",
    "answerText": " Venice (Italy)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71333,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Das Kapital”?",
    "answerText": " Karl Marx"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71334,
    "questionText": " Which was the first Printing Press in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " CMS Press Kottayam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71335,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of Four Stroke Engine?",
    "answerText": " Nikolaus Lotto"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71336,
    "questionText": " Plant ecology is the study of ?",
    "answerText": " Role of plants in the environment"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71337,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Principle of Mathematics”?",
    "answerText": " Bertrand Russel"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71338,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Mother”?",
    "answerText": " Maxim Gorky"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71339,
    "questionText": " ‘Shakuntala’ is a famous painting of?",
    "answerText": " Raja Ravi Varma"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71340,
    "questionText": " The Malayali Memorial was a movement against?",
    "answerText": " The appointment of Tamil Brahmins in Government Service."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71341,
    "questionText": " In which year the High Court of Travancore was established?",
    "answerText": 1887
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71342,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Spycatcher”?",
    "answerText": " Peter Wright"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71343,
    "questionText": " Which is the world's highest and longest highland railway ?",
    "answerText": " The Qinghai-Tibet Railway (l;1142 Km) opened on 1st July 2006 in China"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71344,
    "questionText": " The Last Supper' a fresco painting in Milan; is a famous painting of ?",
    "answerText": " Leonardo Da Vinci"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71345,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of End of an Era ?",
    "answerText": " C S Pandit"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71346,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Rip Van Winkle”?",
    "answerText": " Washington Irving"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71347,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of Relativity; theory of?",
    "answerText": " A.Einstein"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71348,
    "questionText": " The Currency of India?",
    "answerText": " Rupee"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71349,
    "questionText": " The Currency of Jamaica?",
    "answerText": " Jamaican Pound"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71350,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ The Inheritance of Loss”?",
    "answerText": " Kiran Desai"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71351,
    "questionText": " Bandus are the Negroes living in ?",
    "answerText": " Central and South Africa"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71352,
    "questionText": " In which century Jainism reached in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " 3rd Century BC."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71353,
    "questionText": " Earliest coins were believed to have been used by ?",
    "answerText": " The Egyptians"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71354,
    "questionText": " Ethnobotany is the study of ?",
    "answerText": " Relationship between humans and plants"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71355,
    "questionText": " Which is the first Malayalam newspaper that started its internet edition?",
    "answerText": " Deepika in 1997"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71356,
    "questionText": " The animals which derives their food from faecal matters are known as?",
    "answerText": " Coprophytes"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71357,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of New Dimensions of India's Foreign Policy ?",
    "answerText": " Atal Bihari Vajpayee"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71358,
    "questionText": " Which is the largest elephant park in the world?",
    "answerText": " Punnathur Kotta Elephant Sanctuary"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71359,
    "questionText": " Longest Railway (World)?",
    "answerText": " T r a n - S i b e r i a n Railway from Moscow to Nakhodka; 9438 km."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71360,
    "questionText": " Mushika Vamsa Mahakavya was written by poet ?",
    "answerText": " Athula"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71361,
    "questionText": " The Hebrew word Thorah' means?",
    "answerText": " 'to lead'"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71362,
    "questionText": " The Goal of Cartegena Protocol was?",
    "answerText": " To preserve bio diversity & Bio-safety protocols"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71363,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “The Judgement”?",
    "answerText": " Kuldip Nayar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71364,
    "questionText": " The Currency of Honduras?",
    "answerText": " Lempira"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71365,
    "questionText": " Which missionary is the author of Keralappazhama?",
    "answerText": " Dr.Herman Gundert"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71366,
    "questionText": " ദേശീയ മനുഷ്യാവകാശ കമ്മിഷനെ നിയമിക്കുന്നത് ? ",
    "answerText": " രാഷ്ട്രപതി "
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71367,
    "questionText": " The birthplace of Sree Narayana Guru was?",
    "answerText": " Chernpazhanthy in Trivandrum district on 20 August 1855 (Vayalvarathu Veedu)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71368,
    "questionText": " Time and Money was written by ?Friedrich Hayek",
    "answerText": " Friedrich Hayek"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71369,
    "questionText": " Who was the editor of 'Malayali' published from Kollam?",
    "answerText": " Swadeshabhimani Ramakrishnapilla"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71370,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Kavya Narthaki “?",
    "answerText": " Changampuzha Krishna Pilla"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71371,
    "questionText": " Who discovered Monsoon winds in 45 AD ?",
    "answerText": " Hippalus"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71372,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Rainbow ?",
    "answerText": " Pearl S. Buck"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71373,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Magic seeds”?",
    "answerText": " V.S.Naipaul"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71374,
    "questionText": " Which writer is known a Bepoor Sulthan”?",
    "answerText": " Vaikom Muhammed Basheer"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71375,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Kerala Sahitya Charitham (5 vol 7 part) “?",
    "answerText": " Uloor S Parameshwara Iyer"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71376,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of 'Vedanta Saram?",
    "answerText": " Chatampi Swamikal"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71377,
    "questionText": " The functional unit of kidneys is called ?",
    "answerText": " Nephron"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71378,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Mayor of Casterbridge”?",
    "answerText": " Thomas Hardy"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71379,
    "questionText": " American Capitalism was written by ?",
    "answerText": " John Kenneth Galbraith"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71380,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of . Lady with the Lap Dog?",
    "answerText": " Anton Chekhov"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71381,
    "questionText": " Longest combined Highway?",
    "answerText": " The Yangtse River Bridge"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71382,
    "questionText": " A well known German philosopher who argued that God is dead and therefore people were free to create their own values is?",
    "answerText": " Friedrich Nietzsche"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71383,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of Airplane with motor?",
    "answerText": " Orville and Wright"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71384,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “The Grass is singing”?",
    "answerText": " Doris Lessing"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71385,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Kashmir A Tragedy of Errors?",
    "answerText": " Tavleen Singh"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71386,
    "questionText": " Swine flue is caused by ?",
    "answerText": " H1N1 Virus"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71387,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Marthanda Varma “?",
    "answerText": " CV Raman Pillai"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71388,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Principia ?",
    "answerText": " Isaac Newton"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71389,
    "questionText": " Which country is the largest producer of Coal in the world?",
    "answerText": " China"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71390,
    "questionText": " Which missionary is the author of Varthamanapustakam (1785)?",
    "answerText": " Paramekkal Thomakathanar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71391,
    "questionText": " Industrial Revolution gave rise to ?",
    "answerText": " Capitalism"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71392,
    "questionText": " The Punnapra Vayalar Upheaval occured in ?",
    "answerText": " 1-Sep-46"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71393,
    "questionText": " Smallest bird is?",
    "answerText": " Humming bird"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71394,
    "questionText": " The Capital of Vanuatu?",
    "answerText": " Vila"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71395,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “The Upturned Soil”?",
    "answerText": " Mikhail Sholokhov"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71396,
    "questionText": " Ferozepur is on the bank of which River?",
    "answerText": " Sutlej"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71397,
    "questionText": " ദേശീയ മനുഷ്യാവകാശ കമ്മിഷനിലെ അംഗങ്ങളുടെ എണ്ണം? ",
    "answerText": 5
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71398,
    "questionText": " Who was the producer and direction of the first silent movie Vigathakumaran?",
    "answerText": " JC Daniel"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71399,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Some Inner Fury”?",
    "answerText": " Kamala Markandaya"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71400,
    "questionText": " Which is the Sangham work that mentions about the spread of Buddhism in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Manimekhalai"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71401,
    "questionText": " Who was the Kurichya leader who assisted Pazhassi Raja in the guerilla warfare ?",
    "answerText": " Talakkal Chandu"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71402,
    "questionText": " Costliest City (World)?",
    "answerText": " London"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71403,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of Electric Current; Induction of?",
    "answerText": " Michael Faraday"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71404,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Karutha pakshiyude pattu”?",
    "answerText": " O.N.V Kurup"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71405,
    "questionText": " Which King of Travancore formulated the first Legislative Council in an Indian State in 1888?",
    "answerText": " Sri Mulam Thirunal"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71406,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of The Power and Glory?",
    "answerText": " Graham Greene"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71407,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Ape and Essence ?",
    "answerText": " Aldus Huxley"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71408,
    "questionText": " After independence on which date the High Court of Travancore- Cochin was inaugurated with its seat at Ernakulam?",
    "answerText": " 7th of July 1949"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71409,
    "questionText": " and Railway Bridge?",
    "answerText": " 6; 772 m rail deck and 4; 589 road deck (Nanking; China)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71410,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Beyond Belief”?",
    "answerText": " V.S.Naipaul"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71411,
    "questionText": " Sri Narayana Guru died on?",
    "answerText": " 20 September 1928 (1104 Kanni 5) at Sivagiri."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71412,
    "questionText": " Who is known as Lady with the Lamp ?",
    "answerText": " Florence Nightingale"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71413,
    "questionText": " ….is an economy in which there are economic activities between domestic community and outside?",
    "answerText": " Open economy"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71414,
    "questionText": " Which town is the first in India to have achieved 100% literacy?",
    "answerText": " Kottayam town"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71415,
    "questionText": " Who is known as Father of Immunology ?",
    "answerText": " Edward Jenner"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71416,
    "questionText": " Madras Rubber factory (MRF) was established at?",
    "answerText": " Kottayam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71417,
    "questionText": " Who is the creator of the famous characters Brutus; Claudius; Cleopatra?",
    "answerText": " Shakespeare"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71418,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Bend in the Ganges”?",
    "answerText": " Manohar Malgonkar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71419,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Randidangazhi”?",
    "answerText": " Thakazhi Siva Sankara Pillai"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71420,
    "questionText": " The Capital of Maldives?",
    "answerText": " Male"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71421,
    "questionText": " Julius Caesar was assassinated in ?",
    "answerText": " 44BC by Casius; Brutus and other senators"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71422,
    "questionText": " Forest Research Institute is located at?",
    "answerText": " Dehra Dun (Uttar Pradesh)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71423,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Satanic Verses”?",
    "answerText": " Salman Rushdie"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71424,
    "questionText": " Jawaharlal Nehru Botanic Garden and Research Instituteis at ?",
    "answerText": " Palode; Kerala"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71425,
    "questionText": " Which state in India has the highest Human Development Index?",
    "answerText": " Kerala"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71426,
    "questionText": " Which is the largest Latin American country in area and population?",
    "answerText": " Brazil"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71427,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Flight to Parliament?",
    "answerText": " Rajesh Pilot"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71428,
    "questionText": " The first Post-Office in Travancore (also of Kerala) was opened at Alleppey during the reign of?",
    "answerText": " Utram Thirunal Marthanda Varma in 1857."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71429,
    "questionText": " Vasco Da Gama's second visit to Kerala was in?",
    "answerText": 1502
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71430,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Culture in the Vanity Bag”?",
    "answerText": " Nirad C. Chauduri"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71431,
    "questionText": " The Currency of Fiji?",
    "answerText": " Dollar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71432,
    "questionText": " Which is the first country formed in the western part of Africa is ?",
    "answerText": " Ghana."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71433,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “To Light a Candle”?",
    "answerText": " Welthy Fisher"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71434,
    "questionText": " First President of the USA?",
    "answerText": " George Washington"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71435,
    "questionText": " National Institute of Community Development is located at?",
    "answerText": " Hyderabad (Andhra Pradesh)."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71436,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Sceptred Flute”?",
    "answerText": " Sarojini Naidu"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71437,
    "questionText": " Who is known as Indian Machiavelli ?",
    "answerText": " Kautilya"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71438,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Indian Homerule?",
    "answerText": " Gandhiji"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71439,
    "questionText": " A person with group AB can receive any other group. So AB is called?",
    "answerText": " Universal Recipient"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71440,
    "questionText": " The Capital of Peru?",
    "answerText": " Lima"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71441,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Razor's Edge ?",
    "answerText": " W Somerset Maugham"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71442,
    "questionText": " Who was the first Chief Justice of America ?",
    "answerText": " John Jai (1789-95)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71443,
    "questionText": " A poem that mourns on someone's death is called?",
    "answerText": " Elegy"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71444,
    "questionText": " Central Leather Research Institute is located at?",
    "answerText": " Chennai (Tamil Nadu)."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71445,
    "questionText": " Blue Mountains?",
    "answerText": " Nilgiris Hills"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71446,
    "questionText": " Water Frame was invented by?",
    "answerText": " Richard Archwright"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71447,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “The Grapes of Wrath”?",
    "answerText": " John Steinbuck"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71448,
    "questionText": " Man is born free but everywhere he is in chains is a quote of?",
    "answerText": " Rousseau."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71449,
    "questionText": " Davis Cup is associated with?",
    "answerText": " Tennis / Lawn Tennis"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71450,
    "questionText": " Which is the biggest irrigation project in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Kallada IrrigationProject (KIP)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71451,
    "questionText": " The scientific name of Penguin is?",
    "answerText": " Aptenodytes forsteri"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71452,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Essays for Poor to the Rich”?",
    "answerText": " JohnKenneth Galbraith"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71453,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Duravastha”?",
    "answerText": " Kumaranasan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71454,
    "questionText": " Which is the oldest newspaper that is still being published in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " The Deepika"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71455,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Midnight's Children”?",
    "answerText": " Salman Rushdie"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71456,
    "questionText": " Which are the 3 central prisons in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Trivandrum Viyyur (Thrissur) and Kannur"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71457,
    "questionText": " Which Chief Minister of Kerala ruled for the shortest term?",
    "answerText": " C.H. Mahamed Koya"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71458,
    "questionText": " The circulation of blood in the body is regulated by ?",
    "answerText": " Heart"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71459,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Kashmir- Behind the Vale”?",
    "answerText": " MJ. Akbar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71460,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of World Wide Web?",
    "answerText": " Tim Berners Lee"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71461,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Magic Mountain ?",
    "answerText": " Thomas Mann"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71462,
    "questionText": " Which is the worshipping centre of the Jews?",
    "answerText": " Synagogue"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71463,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Robe ?",
    "answerText": " The L.C. Douglas"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71464,
    "questionText": " Greece is on the coast of which sea?",
    "answerText": " The Mediterranean sea"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71465,
    "questionText": " Which is the most populous continent?",
    "answerText": " Asia"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71466,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Pamela?",
    "answerText": " Samuel Richardson."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71467,
    "questionText": " The first electronic computer which could store programs in the memory 'EDVAC' (Electronics Discrete Variable Computer) was invented by ?",
    "answerText": " John Von Neumann in 1945"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71468,
    "questionText": " The residence of American President got the name White House during the period of ?",
    "answerText": " Theodor Roosevelt"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71469,
    "questionText": " What is the number of milk teeth in human body?",
    "answerText": 20
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71470,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Crisis into Chaos?",
    "answerText": " E.M.S.Namboodiripad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71471,
    "questionText": " The Beckal fort was built by?",
    "answerText": " Sivappa Nayaka."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71472,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “The Republic”?",
    "answerText": " Plato"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71473,
    "questionText": " Who is the creator of the famous character “Anandha Padmanabhan”",
    "answerText": " C.V.Ramanpilla"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71474,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Cancer Ward?",
    "answerText": " Alexander Solzhenitsyn"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71475,
    "questionText": " In which country Democracy originated ?",
    "answerText": " Greece"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71476,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Shahnama”?",
    "answerText": " Firdausi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71477,
    "questionText": " Nattakam Travancore Cements is located at?",
    "answerText": " Kottayam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71478,
    "questionText": " Laser Printer was first Introduced by ?",
    "answerText": " IBM"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71479,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Friends and Foes?",
    "answerText": " Sheikh Mujibur Rehman"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71480,
    "questionText": " Chittagong is on the bank of which River?",
    "answerText": " Maiyani"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71481,
    "questionText": " The Currency of Iceland?",
    "answerText": " Krona"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71482,
    "questionText": " Time taken to complete the construction of the Great Pyramid in Egypt?",
    "answerText": " 20 years"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71483,
    "questionText": " Land of Lakes?",
    "answerText": " Scotland"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71484,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Post Office; The (Dak Ghar)”?",
    "answerText": " Rabindranath Tagore"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71485,
    "questionText": " First Woman Prime Minister of India?",
    "answerText": " Mrs. Indira Gandhi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71486,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Dharmaraja and Rama Raja Bhadur”?",
    "answerText": " CV Raman Pillai"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71487,
    "questionText": " Peruvannamuzhi Crocodile Centre is in?",
    "answerText": " Kozhikkode"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71488,
    "questionText": " Coagulation of blood is the function of ?",
    "answerText": " Fibrinogen"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71489,
    "questionText": " The first Opium War was fought during ?",
    "answerText": " 1839- 42"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71490,
    "questionText": " Who was the first European navigator; to reach India by sea route?",
    "answerText": " Vasco Da Gama."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71491,
    "questionText": " One who is devoted to books only for learning facts just for the purpose of scoring marks is called a?",
    "answerText": " Book worm"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71492,
    "questionText": " The Currency of Canada?",
    "answerText": " Dollar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71493,
    "questionText": " Oru Desathinte Katha is the work of?",
    "answerText": " S K Pottakkad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71494,
    "questionText": " The Capital of Mozambique?",
    "answerText": " Maputo"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71495,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Farewell to Arms ?",
    "answerText": " Ernest Hemingway"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71496,
    "questionText": " Pazhassi was killed on the banks of which river?",
    "answerText": " ‘Mavilathode’."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71497,
    "questionText": " The first programmable machine ever designed is ?",
    "answerText": " Analytical Engine."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71498,
    "questionText": " Largest University Building?",
    "answerText": " University of Riyadh.; Saudi Arabia."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71499,
    "questionText": " The Britain passed the Stamp Act in American colonies in ?",
    "answerText": 1765
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71500,
    "questionText": " Lucknow is on the bank of which River?",
    "answerText": " Gomati"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71501,
    "questionText": " Calcium level in blood decreases; name the decease?",
    "answerText": " Tetany"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71502,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Midsummer Night's Dream”?",
    "answerText": " Shakespeare"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71503,
    "questionText": " Who was the first secretary of Kerala Pradesh Congress Committee?",
    "answerText": " K. Madhavan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71504,
    "questionText": " Which district is known as land of gods?",
    "answerText": " Kasaragod"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71505,
    "questionText": " Who is known as Fuehrer ?",
    "answerText": " Adolf Hitler"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71506,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Jurassic Park ?",
    "answerText": " Michael Crichton"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71507,
    "questionText": " Who is the creator of the famous character “Surya Nambothiripadu”",
    "answerText": " O. Chandu Menon"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71508,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Odayil Ninnu “?",
    "answerText": " P. Kesava Dev"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71509,
    "questionText": " Panama Canal was opened in ?",
    "answerText": 1914
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71510,
    "questionText": " Name the first bank in the world?",
    "answerText": " Royal Bank of Scotland in 1728"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71511,
    "questionText": " Malayalam telegraph was started in?",
    "answerText": 1994
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71512,
    "questionText": " Name the first E-governance programme launched in Karnataka?",
    "answerText": " Mahiti"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71513,
    "questionText": " The Capital of Antigua & Barbuda?",
    "answerText": " St.John’s"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71514,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Naricheerukal”?",
    "answerText": " Madhavikutty (Kamala Surayya)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71515,
    "questionText": " സംസ്ഥാന മനുഷ്യാവകാശ കമ്മിഷൻ ചെയർമാനാകാനുള്ള യോഗ്യത? ",
    "answerText": " ഹൈക്കോടതി ചീഫ് ജസ്റ്റിസ് പദവി വഹിച്ച ആളായിരിക്കണം "
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71516,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Himalayan Blunder?",
    "answerText": " J.P. Dalvi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71517,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Scholar Extraordinary”?",
    "answerText": " Nirad C. Chauduri"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71518,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “The Unknown Man; ”?",
    "answerText": " Lewis Carrol"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71519,
    "questionText": " Largest land animal is ?",
    "answerText": " African Elephant (wt. 7 tones)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71520,
    "questionText": " Who is known as a sportsman among kings and king among Sportsmen?",
    "answerText": " Col. Godavarma Raja"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71521,
    "questionText": " Kuttiyadi Dam is located in?",
    "answerText": " Malappuram"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71522,
    "questionText": " Genetic information inhuman beings is stored in?",
    "answerText": " DNA"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71523,
    "questionText": " Oldest University?",
    "answerText": " University of Karueein founded in AD 859; Morocco"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71524,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of Thermometer?",
    "answerText": " Fahrenheit"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71525,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “‘Voice of Conscience’; ”?",
    "answerText": " V.V.Giri"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71526,
    "questionText": " Guwahati is on the bank of which River?",
    "answerText": " Brahmaputra"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71527,
    "questionText": " Which district is declared the first polio-free district in India?",
    "answerText": " Pathanamthitta"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71528,
    "questionText": " Who created the first vaccine for rabies?",
    "answerText": " Louis Pasteur"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71529,
    "questionText": " Largest Museum (World)?",
    "answerText": " American Museum of Natural History; New York city. It comprises 19 interconnected buildings with 23 acres of floor space."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71530,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “The Power and Glory”?",
    "answerText": " Graham Greene"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71531,
    "questionText": " Dhyan Chand Trophy is associated with?",
    "answerText": " Hockey"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71532,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Kaalam”?",
    "answerText": " M.T.Vasudevan Nair"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71533,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Duchess of Malfi ?",
    "answerText": " John Webster"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71534,
    "questionText": " The voyage of the Beagle is the book written by ?",
    "answerText": " Charles Darwin"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71535,
    "questionText": " The first Olympic Games were held at Olympia in Greece in ?",
    "answerText": " 776 Bc"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71536,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Sreekrishna Karnamritham.”?",
    "answerText": " Poonthanam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71537,
    "questionText": " VISA is ?",
    "answerText": " Visa International Services Association"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71538,
    "questionText": " World habitat day is ?",
    "answerText": " 1st Monday of October"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71539,
    "questionText": " The method of sending message by wire was invented by?",
    "answerText": " Morse in 1835"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71540,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “The Prince; ”?",
    "answerText": " Machiavelli"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71541,
    "questionText": " The Goal of Kyoto protocol was ?",
    "answerText": " To reduce the emissions of Green House Gases (GHGs)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71542,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Poverty and Famine ?",
    "answerText": " Amartya Sen"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71543,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Adam Bede?",
    "answerText": " George Eliot"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71544,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of Cinematography?",
    "answerText": " Thomas Edison"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71545,
    "questionText": " Pazhassiraja Art Gallery is in?"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71546,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Savithri”?",
    "answerText": " Aurobindo Ghosh"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71547,
    "questionText": " Kaveri river originates from?",
    "answerText": " Kottencheri hills near Talakaveri in Kasaragod"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71548,
    "questionText": " Where is the Indo-Swiz Project situated?",
    "answerText": " Mattuppetti."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71549,
    "questionText": " Where is the headquarters of Calicut University?",
    "answerText": " Thenjippalam in Malappuram district."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71550,
    "questionText": " English king who was trialed and executed publically in 1649?",
    "answerText": " Charles I"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71551,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Henry Esmond ?",
    "answerText": " William M Thackeray"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71552,
    "questionText": " Who called Ayyankali as 'PulayaRaja'?",
    "answerText": " Gandhiji"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71553,
    "questionText": " The Currency of Yemen?",
    "answerText": " Rial"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71554,
    "questionText": " Tallest Animal in the world is ?",
    "answerText": " Giraffe"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71555,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Prison Diary?",
    "answerText": " Jayaprakash Narayan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71556,
    "questionText": " In plants which carries prepared food from leaves to all parts of plant?",
    "answerText": " Phloem"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71557,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “The Indo-Pakistani Conflict”?",
    "answerText": " Russell Brines"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71558,
    "questionText": " Holy Ka aba was built by?",
    "answerText": " Prophet Ebrahim"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71559,
    "questionText": " Which is the eastern boundary of Kerala?",
    "answerText": " The Sahyadris"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71560,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of Fountain Pen?",
    "answerText": " Waterman"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71561,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Mahabharata ?",
    "answerText": " Maharishi Ved Vyas"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71562,
    "questionText": " Aranmula is a major attraction for its famous?",
    "answerText": " Metal Mirrors"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71563,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “House of the Dead”?",
    "answerText": " Fyodor Dostoevsky"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71564,
    "questionText": " Which American President ruled the least term?",
    "answerText": " William Henry Harrison"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71565,
    "questionText": " Which film is India's first neorealistic film?",
    "answerText": " Newspaper Boy (1958)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71566,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of Galvanometer?",
    "answerText": " Sweigger"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71567,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Chekerunna Pakshikal”?",
    "answerText": " Madhavikutty (Kamala Surayya)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71568,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “The Metamorphosis”?",
    "answerText": " Franz Kafka"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71569,
    "questionText": " Which is considered to be the first internet search engine allowing people to find specific files?",
    "answerText": " Archie - (Anomymous FTP)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71570,
    "questionText": " In which year Ireland was delinked from the United Kingdom of Great Britain and Ireland?",
    "answerText": 1921
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71571,
    "questionText": " Which organ of the body is affected by Malaria?",
    "answerText": " RBC"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71572,
    "questionText": " The scientific name of Rabbit is?",
    "answerText": " Oryctolagus cuniculas"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71573,
    "questionText": " Widal Test is used to diagnose?",
    "answerText": " Typhoid"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71574,
    "questionText": " SARS (Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome) a lung disease; is caused by ?",
    "answerText": " Corona Virus"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71575,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Poverty and Famines?",
    "answerText": " Dr Amartya Sen"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71576,
    "questionText": " Vasco Da Gama reached Kerala for the third time in ?",
    "answerText": 1524
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71577,
    "questionText": " Which fish is called mosquito fish?",
    "answerText": " Gambusia"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71578,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Zulfi; My Friend”?",
    "answerText": " Philoo Mody"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71579,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Farewell The Trumpets”?",
    "answerText": " James Morris"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71580,
    "questionText": " The word Heirogliphic means?",
    "answerText": " Sacred Writing"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71581,
    "questionText": " Epsom (England) is associated with which Sport?",
    "answerText": " Derby Horse Races"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71582,
    "questionText": " Kolkata is on the bank of which River?",
    "answerText": " Hooghly"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71583,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Choice of techniques?",
    "answerText": " Dr Amartya Sen"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71584,
    "questionText": " Napolean Bonaparte died in the year?",
    "answerText": 1821
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71585,
    "questionText": " Who known as Kerala Valmiki”?",
    "answerText": " Vallathol Narayana Menon"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71586,
    "questionText": " Who is the creator of the famous character “Thirumukathu Pilla”",
    "answerText": " c.V.Ramanpilla"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71587,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of Radio signals?",
    "answerText": " G.Marconi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71588,
    "questionText": " MCC Trophy is associated with?",
    "answerText": " Hockey"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71589,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Crime and Punishment?",
    "answerText": " Fydor Dostoevskey"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71590,
    "questionText": " Mussolini organised his followers into the?",
    "answerText": " 'Black shirts' In"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71591,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Patriot ?",
    "answerText": " Pearl S Buck"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71592,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “The Eye of the Storm”?",
    "answerText": " Patrick White"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71593,
    "questionText": " The United Nations Monetary and Financial Conference; a gathering of delegates from 44 nations that convened from July 1 to 22; 1944 in Bretton Woods; New Hampshire is better known as ?",
    "answerText": " The Bretton Woods Conference"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71594,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of Xenon?",
    "answerText": " W.Ramsay & M.Travers"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71595,
    "questionText": " The writing system of the Sumerians was known as?",
    "answerText": " Cunieform"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71596,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Brides Book of Beauty”?",
    "answerText": " Mulk Raj Anand"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71597,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “As I See ?",
    "answerText": " Kiran Bedi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71598,
    "questionText": " In which lake Nehru Trophy Boat race is conducted?",
    "answerText": " Punnamada lake"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71599,
    "questionText": " 'The Praise of Folly' was a satiristic work written by ?",
    "answerText": " Erasmus"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71600,
    "questionText": " Purification or purgation of emotions; through drama is called?",
    "answerText": " Catharsis"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71601,
    "questionText": " Njanappana was written by?",
    "answerText": " Poonthanam Namboodiri"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71602,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Essays on Gita”?",
    "answerText": " Aurobindo Ghosh"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71603,
    "questionText": " Name the first American Lady who advocated for the rights of women is?",
    "answerText": " Abey Gale Smith (Wife of John Adams)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71604,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Chithirappavai”?",
    "answerText": " P.Y.Akilandam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71605,
    "questionText": " ദേശീയ മനുഷ്യാവകാശ കമ്മിഷൻ അംഗമായ ആദ്യ വനിത? ",
    "answerText": " ഫാത്തിമബീവി "
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71606,
    "questionText": " In Kerala which region is known as the home of circus?",
    "answerText": " Thalassery inKannur"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71607,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Emperor Jones (Drama)”?",
    "answerText": " Eugine O'Neil"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71608,
    "questionText": " Pearl Harbour attack was on ?",
    "answerText": " 7th December 1941"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71609,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Coolie”?",
    "answerText": " Mulk Raj Anand"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71610,
    "questionText": " Macao; which was a colony of the Portugal was restored to China on?",
    "answerText": " 20th December 1999"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71611,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of The Treasure Island?",
    "answerText": " R.L. Stevenson"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71612,
    "questionText": " The State of Kerala was formed on?"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71613,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Expanding Universe ?",
    "answerText": " Arthur Stanley Eddington"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71614,
    "questionText": " Napoleon died in the year??",
    "answerText": 1821
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71615,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Treasure Island ?",
    "answerText": " Robert Louis Stevenson"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71616,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Sultry Days”?",
    "answerText": " Shobha De"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71617,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Painter of Signs”?",
    "answerText": " R.K. Narayan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71618,
    "questionText": " Who made the first strong roads in England with the help of small stones?",
    "answerText": " John Macadam; an engineer of Scotland"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71619,
    "questionText": " The first dynasty in the world was established at ?",
    "answerText": " Ur in Sumeriain 3000BC"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71620,
    "questionText": " The Sri Mulam Popular Assembly (Praja Sabha) was formed by Sri MulamThirunal in ?",
    "answerText": 1904
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71621,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Dr. Faust”?",
    "answerText": " Goethe"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71622,
    "questionText": " Liberty; Equality and Fraternity was the slogan which Revolution?",
    "answerText": " French Revolution"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71623,
    "questionText": " Ezhava Memorial was in ?",
    "answerText": 1896
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71624,
    "questionText": " Which was the capital city of Arakkal family; the only Muslim Sultanate of Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Kannur"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71625,
    "questionText": " Plant anatomy is the study of ?",
    "answerText": " Cell and tissue structure"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71626,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Spanish Tragedy”?",
    "answerText": " Thomas Kyd"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71627,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “The Golden Gate”?",
    "answerText": " Vikram Seth"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71628,
    "questionText": " Who is the creator of the famous character “Keeran Poosari”",
    "answerText": " S.K. Pottakadu"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71629,
    "questionText": " The Capital of Oman?",
    "answerText": " Muscat"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71630,
    "questionText": " Saivite saints were called ?",
    "answerText": " Nayanars"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71631,
    "questionText": " Dorian Gray",
    "answerText": " Oscar Wilde"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71632,
    "questionText": " Coldest Planet?",
    "answerText": " Pluto"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71633,
    "questionText": " The Capital of Cape Verde?",
    "answerText": " Praia"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71634,
    "questionText": " The Capital of Grenada?",
    "answerText": " St.George’s"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71635,
    "questionText": " World health day is observed every year on ?",
    "answerText": " April 7th."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71636,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Strangers and Brothers”?",
    "answerText": " C.P.Snow"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71637,
    "questionText": " City of Rome was bilt by by ?",
    "answerText": " Romulas and Remus"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71638,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of Quantum Theory?",
    "answerText": " Max Planck"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71639,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Shape of Things to Come?",
    "answerText": " H G Wells"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71640,
    "questionText": " The United Nations Commission On International Trade Law (UNCITRAL) was established in?",
    "answerText": 1996
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71641,
    "questionText": " which grow in soil?",
    "answerText": " Terrestrial"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71642,
    "questionText": " Great Depression of 1990 was written by ?",
    "answerText": " Ravi Batra"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71643,
    "questionText": " By which treaty Travancore accepted the Supremacy of the Company?",
    "answerText": " The treaty of 1795"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71644,
    "questionText": " India's first Eco-Tourism programme was started in 1998 in?",
    "answerText": " Thenmala in Kollam district"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71645,
    "questionText": " Cologne is on the bank of which River?",
    "answerText": " Rhine"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71646,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ In the company of women lave Truth and a little Malice”?",
    "answerText": " Khushwant Singh"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71647,
    "questionText": " Who is considered as the father of the nation of Bolivia?",
    "answerText": " Simon Bolivor"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71648,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of The Trail?",
    "answerText": " Franz Kafka"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71649,
    "questionText": " A moral story is called?",
    "answerText": " Fable"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71650,
    "questionText": " Bose Research Institute is located at?",
    "answerText": " Kolkata (W.Bengal)."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71651,
    "questionText": " The year in which Anchal Service was amalgamated with Telegraph department is?",
    "answerText": " April 1951."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71652,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Tamas”?",
    "answerText": " Bhishma Sahni"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71653,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of Skyscraper?",
    "answerText": " Baron Jenny"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71654,
    "questionText": " Fastest Bird?",
    "answerText": " Swift"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71655,
    "questionText": " The Currency of Thailand?",
    "answerText": " Baht"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71656,
    "questionText": " The Currency of Denmark?",
    "answerText": " Krone"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71657,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of I Follow the Mahatma?",
    "answerText": " K.M.Munshi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71658,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of Arc Lamp?",
    "answerText": " C.F.Brush"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71659,
    "questionText": " The Capital of Comoros?",
    "answerText": " Moroni"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71660,
    "questionText": " Who was the first Rajya Sabha member to become the Chief Minister of Kerala?",
    "answerText": " C.Achuthamenon"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71661,
    "questionText": " Excessive alcoholic consumption causes ?",
    "answerText": " Liver Cirrhosis"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71662,
    "questionText": " Indian Cancer Research Centre is located in?",
    "answerText": " Mumbai"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71663,
    "questionText": " The Capital of Tunisia?",
    "answerText": " Tunis"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71664,
    "questionText": " The Currency of Guinea-Bissau?",
    "answerText": " Peso"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71665,
    "questionText": " Which was the first Colour Film ?",
    "answerText": " Kandam Becha Coat"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71666,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Human Factor”?",
    "answerText": " Graham Greene"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71667,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “The Glass Palace”?",
    "answerText": " Amitav Ghosh"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71668,
    "questionText": " The city of Constantinople was founded by?",
    "answerText": " Constantine"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71669,
    "questionText": " The Ramsar Convention(1971) is an international treaty for the conservation and sustainable utilisation of wetlands. It was held at?",
    "answerText": " Ramsar in Iran"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71670,
    "questionText": " First Chinese pilgrim to visit India?",
    "answerText": " Fa-Hein"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71671,
    "questionText": " Asia Cup is associated with?",
    "answerText": " Cricket"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71672,
    "questionText": " Which is the smallest village in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Kudayathoor of Thodupuzha taluk"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71673,
    "questionText": " Saha Institute of Nuclear Physics is located at?",
    "answerText": " Kolkata (West Bengal)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71674,
    "questionText": " The first real mechanical calculating machine is ?",
    "answerText": " Pascaline."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71675,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of The Illusion of Destiny?",
    "answerText": " Prof.Amartya Sen"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71676,
    "questionText": " Who is the creator of the famous characters Juliet; Miranda; Othello;?",
    "answerText": " Shakespeare"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71677,
    "questionText": " Chitranjali Studio is founded and managed by?",
    "answerText": " KSFDC"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71678,
    "questionText": " ASCII stands for?",
    "answerText": " American Standard Code for Information Interchange"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71679,
    "questionText": " A sculpture Mother and Child by Kanayi Kunhiraman is found at?",
    "answerText": " Payyambalam Beach"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71680,
    "questionText": " Western Blot test is used to diagnose?",
    "answerText": " Aids"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71681,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Life Divine ?",
    "answerText": " Aurobindo Ghosh"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71682,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of Telescope?",
    "answerText": " Galileo"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71683,
    "questionText": " Rabies; caused by a virus; affects which part of human body?",
    "answerText": " The nerve cells of the brain."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71684,
    "questionText": " The Ministerial Council; the supreme organ of the WTO has to meet at least?",
    "answerText": " Once in every two years"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71685,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Inside Asia”?",
    "answerText": " John Gunther"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71686,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “The Illusion of Destiny”?",
    "answerText": " Prof.Amartya Sen"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71687,
    "questionText": " During which period of evolution man Family life began ?",
    "answerText": " Neolithic Age"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71688,
    "questionText": " Who is the Pro-Chancellor of Agricultural University in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Agriculture Minister"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71689,
    "questionText": " At the time of declaration of Indian independence Pondicherry was a colony of?",
    "answerText": " France"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71690,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Yanthram”?",
    "answerText": " Malayattoor Ramakrishnan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71691,
    "questionText": " RBI has introduced KYC norms in India to prevent ?",
    "answerText": " Money Laundering"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71692,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Indian Philosophy; ”?",
    "answerText": " Dr. S.Radhakrishnan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71693,
    "questionText": " School of Tropical Medicines is located at?",
    "answerText": " Kolkata (West Bengal)."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71694,
    "questionText": " The Affluent Society was written by ?",
    "answerText": " J.K. Galbraith"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71695,
    "questionText": " Who is the creator of the famous character “Tom Jones”",
    "answerText": " Henry Fielding"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71696,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Vish Vriksha Bankim ?",
    "answerText": " Chandra Chatterjee"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71697,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Enippadikal “?",
    "answerText": " Thakazhi Siva Sankara Pillai"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71698,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of From Rio de Janeiro to Johnnesburg?",
    "answerText": " M.S.Swaminathan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71699,
    "questionText": " Pollination by insects is called?",
    "answerText": " Entomophily"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71700,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “‘Job for Millions’”?",
    "answerText": " V.V.Giri"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71701,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of House of the Dead ?",
    "answerText": " Fyodor Dostoevsky"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71702,
    "questionText": " Hitler's armies invaded Polland on ?",
    "answerText": " 1-Sep-39"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71703,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Kavithadwani”?",
    "answerText": " Dr. M. Leelavathi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71704,
    "questionText": " Most Intelligent Animal?",
    "answerText": " Chimpanzee"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71705,
    "questionText": " World's first woman computer programmer ?",
    "answerText": " Augusta Ada King Ada Lovelace"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71706,
    "questionText": " Great tragedies of Shakespeare are ?",
    "answerText": " 'Hamlet'; 'Macbeth'; 'Othello and King Lear'"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71707,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Job for Millions”?",
    "answerText": " V.V.Giri"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71708,
    "questionText": " Who was the first Prime Minister of England and the first in the world to hold the post of Prime Minister?",
    "answerText": " Robert Walpole"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71709,
    "questionText": " L.SD. (Lysergic acid diethylamide) is obtained from a fungi; called ?",
    "answerText": " Irgot."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71710,
    "questionText": " Who is the creator of the famous characters Mr. Micawber; Jacob Marley;?",
    "answerText": " Charles Dickens"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71711,
    "questionText": " Which district is known as the land of Poorams?",
    "answerText": " Thrissur"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71712,
    "questionText": " Kala-azar (Leishmaniasis) is transmitted by ?",
    "answerText": " Sand flies."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71713,
    "questionText": " The Currency of Guyana?",
    "answerText": " Guyana Dollar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71714,
    "questionText": " Plant morphology is the study of ?",
    "answerText": " Structure and life cycles"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71715,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Sursagar”?",
    "answerText": " Surdas"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71716,
    "questionText": " Land of Kangaroo?",
    "answerText": " Australia"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71717,
    "questionText": " Kerala Police Academy is at?",
    "answerText": " Ramavarmapuram in Thrissur"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71718,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Life Divine?",
    "answerText": " Aurobindo Ghosh"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71719,
    "questionText": " The Currency of Central African Republic?",
    "answerText": " France CFA"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71720,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Descent of Man ?",
    "answerText": " Charles Darwin"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71721,
    "questionText": " To maintain the value of money what must be kept constant?",
    "answerText": " Price Level"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71722,
    "questionText": " Hong Kong was handed over by Britain to China on?",
    "answerText": " July I; 1997"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71723,
    "questionText": " The Capital of Trinidad and Tobago?",
    "answerText": " Port-of-Spain"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71724,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Letters from a Father to his Daughter”?",
    "answerText": " Jawaharlal Nehru"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71725,
    "questionText": " Who is known as the 'the Washington of South'?",
    "answerText": " Simon Bolivor"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71726,
    "questionText": " The early writing of the Egyptians were known as ?",
    "answerText": " Hieroglyphics"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71727,
    "questionText": " Which organ of the body is affected by Tuberculosis?",
    "answerText": " Lungs"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71728,
    "questionText": " The disease which affects the liver is ?",
    "answerText": " Jaundice"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71729,
    "questionText": " A person who used his or her expertise to gain access to other computers to get information illegally or to do damage is called ?",
    "answerText": " Hacker"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71730,
    "questionText": " Padayani is the traditional art of?",
    "answerText": " Pathanamthitta"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71731,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “The True History of Kelley Gang”?",
    "answerText": " Peter Carey"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71732,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of The Lion and the Jewel?",
    "answerText": " Wole Soynika"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71733,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “The End of Imagination”?",
    "answerText": " Arundhati Roy"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71734,
    "questionText": " Peru was discovered by ?",
    "answerText": " Francisco Pizzaro"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71735,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Broken Wings”?",
    "answerText": " Sarojini Naidu"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71736,
    "questionText": " Name of the National School Computerisation Programme is ?",
    "answerText": " Vidya Vahini."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71737,
    "questionText": " Siesmograph was invented by?",
    "answerText": " The Chinese"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71738,
    "questionText": " Who gave the mesage One caste; One Religion; One God for Man at a conference held at the advaitasrama?",
    "answerText": " Sree Narayana Guru"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71739,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Buddha’s Warriors ?",
    "answerText": " Mikel Dunham"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71740,
    "questionText": " Longest Wall (World)?",
    "answerText": " Great Wall of China 2400 km"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71741,
    "questionText": " Fastest Animal?",
    "answerText": " The Peregerine Falcon"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71742,
    "questionText": " Tallest animal on earth is ?",
    "answerText": " Giraffe"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71743,
    "questionText": " Who is known as the Child of the French Revolution?",
    "answerText": " Napolean Bonaparte (1769-1821)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71744,
    "questionText": " Agrarian Reforms in Travancore began during the period of ?",
    "answerText": " Ayilyam Thirunal"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71745,
    "questionText": " The first nursing school was established by?",
    "answerText": " Florence Nightingale"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71746,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Tsunami - 7 Hours that Shook the World ?",
    "answerText": " Satinder Blndra"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71747,
    "questionText": " 8 bits = ?",
    "answerText": " 1 byte."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71748,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Portrait of a Lady?",
    "answerText": " Henry James"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71749,
    "questionText": " Who was the first Malayali to receive the Dronacharya Award (1965)?",
    "answerText": " O M Nambiar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71750,
    "questionText": " Name the Island in which Nelson Mandela was imprisoned?",
    "answerText": " Robert Islands"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71751,
    "questionText": " The Capital of Japan?",
    "answerText": " Tokyo"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71752,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Pygmalion”?",
    "answerText": " George Bernard Shaw"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71753,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Debacle”?",
    "answerText": " Emile Zola"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71754,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Tamas?",
    "answerText": " Bhishma Sahni"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71755,
    "questionText": " The pH value of human blood is nearly ?",
    "answerText": " 7.5."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71756,
    "questionText": " Malayalam became an independent language; freed from Tamil during the period of ?",
    "answerText": " Kulasekharas (9th Century AD)."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71757,
    "questionText": " The Currency of Venezuela?",
    "answerText": " Bolivar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71758,
    "questionText": " Who is the creator of the famous characters Madhavan; Panchu Menon?",
    "answerText": " O. Chandu Menon"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71759,
    "questionText": " Who founded Kerala Kaumudi in 1911?",
    "answerText": " C V Kunhiraman with K Sukumaran"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71760,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of Aniline Dyes?",
    "answerText": " Hoffman"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71761,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Raghuvamsa ?",
    "answerText": " Kalidas"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71762,
    "questionText": " (C.M.S College, the first college in Kerala was started at Kottayam in?",
    "answerText": 1840
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71763,
    "questionText": " Pazhassi tourism centre' is located in?",
    "answerText": " Mananthavady in Wynad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71764,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “The Mill on the Floss”?",
    "answerText": " George Eliot"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71765,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Pickwick Papers”?",
    "answerText": " Charles Dickens"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71766,
    "questionText": " Das Capital was written by ?",
    "answerText": " KarIMarx"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71767,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Ram Charit Manas”?",
    "answerText": " Tulsidas"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71768,
    "questionText": " What was the slogan for the Year of Books (2002)?",
    "answerText": " Books for All and All for Books"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71769,
    "questionText": " Which is the legal tender in a modem society?",
    "answerText": " Currency notes"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71770,
    "questionText": " Name the philosopher who first articulated the concept of Pakistan in 1931?",
    "answerText": " Muhammed Iqbal"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71771,
    "questionText": " Who renamed Leningrad back to St. Petersburg?",
    "answerText": " Gorbachov"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71772,
    "questionText": " The ruler who led England after the Civil Warwas ?",
    "answerText": " Oliver Cromwell"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71773,
    "questionText": " Largest ARCHIPELAGO?",
    "answerText": " Indonesia"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71774,
    "questionText": " Who was the first Congress Chief Minister of Kerala?",
    "answerText": " R. Sankar."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71775,
    "questionText": " Hari Pachanan;",
    "answerText": " C.V.Ramanpilla"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71776,
    "questionText": " The plants which perch on other plants but do not take nourishment from them ?",
    "answerText": " Epiphytes"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71777,
    "questionText": " The biggest source of aid to the third world is ?",
    "answerText": " The World Bank"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71778,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Child who never Grew”?",
    "answerText": " Pearl S Buck"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71779,
    "questionText": " Who were the first to invent the system of Multiplication?",
    "answerText": " Mesopotamians"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71780,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of The Unfinished Dream ?",
    "answerText": " Varghese Kurian"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71781,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of It is Always Possible?",
    "answerText": " Kiran Bedi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71782,
    "questionText": " Which is the first malayalam cinemascope film?",
    "answerText": " Thacholi Ambu (1978) directed by Navodaya Appachan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71783,
    "questionText": " The Government Securities traded in the British Stock Exchange are known as?",
    "answerText": " Government Edge"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71784,
    "questionText": " Bleeding in liver is known as ?",
    "answerText": " Liver Cirrhosis"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71785,
    "questionText": " Who is known as the Architect of Thrissur Town?",
    "answerText": " SakthanThampuran"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71786,
    "questionText": " Who is the creator of the famous characters “Appukili; Ravi; Mollakka”",
    "answerText": " OV.Vijayan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71787,
    "questionText": " Indian Military Academy is located at?",
    "answerText": " Dehra Dun; (Uttar Pradesh)."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71788,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Man for All Seasons”?",
    "answerText": " Robert Bolt"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71789,
    "questionText": " Who is the founder of Pakistan?",
    "answerText": " Muhammed Ali Jinna"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71790,
    "questionText": " Island of Pearls?",
    "answerText": " Bahrain (Persian Gulf)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71791,
    "questionText": " Who was the wife of Socrates?",
    "answerText": " Zantippee"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71792,
    "questionText": " Civil War in England started in the year ?",
    "answerText": 1642
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71793,
    "questionText": " Who was popularly known as Radio Ammavan?",
    "answerText": " P K Veera Raghavan Nair"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71794,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of King Lear ?",
    "answerText": " William Shakespeare"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71795,
    "questionText": " The first book on personal computers “Computer Liberation and Dream Machine”; was written by ?",
    "answerText": " Ted Nelson"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71796,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Issues of Science and Religion?",
    "answerText": " Ian Barbour"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71797,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of God and the Bible '?",
    "answerText": " Mathew Arnol"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71798,
    "questionText": " Chromosomes; other than the sex chromosomes; are called?",
    "answerText": " Autosomes"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71799,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Shivaji; The Great Patriot”?",
    "answerText": " Lala Lajpat Rai"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71800,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Seven summers”?",
    "answerText": " Mulk Raj Anand"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71801,
    "questionText": " The Currency of Oman?",
    "answerText": " Omani Rial"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71802,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Two Women”?",
    "answerText": " Alberto Moravia"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71803,
    "questionText": " Who is the creator of PASCAL language?",
    "answerText": " Nikalus Writh"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71804,
    "questionText": " Name the Plants grow in water?",
    "answerText": " Hydrophytes"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71805,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Androcles and the Lion ?",
    "answerText": " George Bernard Shaw"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71806,
    "questionText": " BEG test is used to diagnose?",
    "answerText": " Brain Diseases"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71807,
    "questionText": " The UN Charter was signed at ?",
    "answerText": " San Francisco on 26th June 1945 by Fifty nations"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71808,
    "questionText": " One gram of fat yields how many calories of energy?",
    "answerText": " 9.3 calories"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71809,
    "questionText": " The state of Kerala formally came into existence on?",
    "answerText": " November 1;1956."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71810,
    "questionText": " Oral Polio vaccine was discovered by ?",
    "answerText": " Albert Bruce Sabin (1955)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71811,
    "questionText": " The first general elections to the Kerala state Legislature were held in ?",
    "answerText": " February and March 1957."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71812,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of The Grass is singing ?",
    "answerText": " Doris Lessing"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71813,
    "questionText": " Which vitamin is considered both as a vitamin and hormone?",
    "answerText": " Vitamin E"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71814,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of The Sound and the Fury?",
    "answerText": " William Faulkner.(Nobel Prize winner for the literature in 1949)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71815,
    "questionText": " In which year Swadeshabhimani Ramakrishnapilla became the editor of Swadeshabhimani in?",
    "answerText": 1906
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71816,
    "questionText": " The Capital of South Africa?",
    "answerText": " Pretoria"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71817,
    "questionText": " The universalisation of education within ten years in the age group of six to fourteen is the aim of?",
    "answerText": " 'Sarva Siksha Abhiyan' (SSA)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71818,
    "questionText": " What ideal is considered as the heart and soul of Renaissance?",
    "answerText": " Humanism"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71819,
    "questionText": " The Capital of Nauru?",
    "answerText": " Yaren Nauru"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71820,
    "questionText": " Where was Swadeshabhimani Ramakrishnapilla born?",
    "answerText": " At Neyyattinkkara in Thriruvananthapuram."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71821,
    "questionText": " Email was introduced by ?",
    "answerText": " Ray Tomilson"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71822,
    "questionText": " Christopher Columbus discovered West Indies and thought it was India in 1492 and called its people?",
    "answerText": " Red Indians"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71823,
    "questionText": " In which country Jasmine revolution began?",
    "answerText": " Tunisia"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71824,
    "questionText": " Headquarters of OPEC is at ?",
    "answerText": " Vienna;(Austria)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71825,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of Railway Engine?",
    "answerText": " Stephenson"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71826,
    "questionText": " Liberty; equality; fraternity;  the slogan of French Revolution; are the words of?",
    "answerText": " Rousseau"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71827,
    "questionText": " Who wrote the history of the Peloponnesian war between Athens and Sparta?",
    "answerText": " Thucydides; a Greek historian"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71828,
    "questionText": " Which was a Paper started by Sahodaran Ayyappan?",
    "answerText": " Sahodaran."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71829,
    "questionText": " Russian parliament was known as ?",
    "answerText": " Duma"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71830,
    "questionText": " The Sahitya academy was shifted to its present location at city of Thrissur on?",
    "answerText": " Sep-57"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71831,
    "questionText": " The Capital of Senegal?",
    "answerText": " Dakar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71832,
    "questionText": " Who wrote The Republic ?",
    "answerText": " Plato"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71833,
    "questionText": " Who described Alappuzha as the Venice of the East?",
    "answerText": " Lord Curzon"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71834,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of My Life; Law and Other Things?",
    "answerText": " M C Setal vad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71835,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Hamsters”?",
    "answerText": " C.P. Snow"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71836,
    "questionText": " Who were hailed for the invention of Addition; Subtraction and Division?",
    "answerText": " Egyptians"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71837,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “(The Social Contract) Leaves of Grass”?",
    "answerText": " Walt Whitman"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71838,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Muslim Dilemma in India?",
    "answerText": " M.R.A Baig"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71839,
    "questionText": " Windy City?",
    "answerText": " Chicago"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71840,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Verukal”?",
    "answerText": " Malayattoor Ramakrishnan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71841,
    "questionText": " Petrograd was renamed again as ?",
    "answerText": " Leningrad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71842,
    "questionText": " National Institute of Fashion Technology is located at?",
    "answerText": " New Delhi."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71843,
    "questionText": " Who is regarded as Father of Modern Travancore?",
    "answerText": " Marthanda Varma who reigned from 1729 to 1758 AD"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71844,
    "questionText": " The Cranganore port (Muziris) declined as' a result of the floods in the Periyar river in?",
    "answerText": 1341
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71845,
    "questionText": " The Presidents rule under the Article 356;was declared in Kerala for the first time on?",
    "answerText": " 31st July 1959."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71846,
    "questionText": " Who became the life time secretary of S.N.D.P Yogam in 1903?",
    "answerText": " Kumaranasan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71847,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of Tank (Military)?",
    "answerText": " Swinton"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71848,
    "questionText": " Garden of England?",
    "answerText": " Kent (England)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71849,
    "questionText": " Who was the first Justice ?",
    "answerText": " Jagdish Bhalla"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71850,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Pakistan Papers”?",
    "answerText": " Mani Shankar Aiyar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71851,
    "questionText": " Who is the only Chief Minister from Muslim Community?",
    "answerText": " C.H. Muhammed Koya"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71852,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of Homoeopathy?",
    "answerText": " Hahnemann"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71853,
    "questionText": " The petition submitted American colonists before king George III of England in 1774?",
    "answerText": " Olive Branch Petition"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71854,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of The Divine Comedy ?",
    "answerText": " Dante"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71855,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of The Google Story ?",
    "answerText": " David A. Vise"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71856,
    "questionText": " The police department is headed by?",
    "answerText": " SPC-State Police Chief"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71857,
    "questionText": " Wealth of Nations was written by ?",
    "answerText": " Adam Smith"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71858,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Against the Grains ?",
    "answerText": " Boris Yeltsin"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71859,
    "questionText": " The first computer magazine 'Computers and Automation' first published by ?",
    "answerText": " Edmund Berkely in 1950."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71860,
    "questionText": " Father of Gene therapy?",
    "answerText": " Anderson"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71861,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “The Vicar of Wakefield”?",
    "answerText": " Oliver Goldsmith"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71862,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of ‘Mohandas Gandhi’?",
    "answerText": " Swadeshabhimani Ramakrishnapilla"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71863,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Vinaypatrika”?",
    "answerText": " Tulsidas"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71864,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Khasakkinte lthihasam”?",
    "answerText": " O.V Vijayan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71865,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Atoms of Hope ?",
    "answerText": " Mohan Sundar Rajan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71866,
    "questionText": " The construction of Old Secretariat complex was completed in?",
    "answerText": 1869
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71867,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Meaning of India”?",
    "answerText": " Raja Rao"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71868,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Heroes and Hero Worship”?",
    "answerText": " Thomas Carlyle"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71869,
    "questionText": " Which city is known as Capital of Chinese economy?",
    "answerText": " Shanghai"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71870,
    "questionText": " First Judge of Supreme Court?",
    "answerText": " Camelia Sorabji"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71871,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Ambassador’s Report”?",
    "answerText": " Chester Bowles"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71872,
    "questionText": " In the Gender Equality Index (GII) published in 2011 India is ranked at?",
    "answerText": " 129th in the world"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71873,
    "questionText": " St Angelo Fort in Kannur was built by?",
    "answerText": " Dom Francisco de Almeida; the first Portuguese Viceroy of India (1505)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71874,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of Gunpowder?",
    "answerText": " Roger Bacon"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71875,
    "questionText": " The coagulation of blood in vessels is prevented during normal condition by ?4",
    "answerText": " Heparin"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71876,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Divine Comedy?",
    "answerText": " A Dante"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71877,
    "questionText": " First man to walk in space?",
    "answerText": " Alexi Leonov (USSR)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71878,
    "questionText": " Nicolo Conte reached Kerala is ?",
    "answerText": " 1440AD."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71879,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Amavasi “?",
    "answerText": " Balachandran Chullikkadu"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71880,
    "questionText": " The Dutch palace or Mattancherry palace was built by?"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71881,
    "questionText": " Name the river that flows through Silent Valley?",
    "answerText": " Kuntipuzha"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71882,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Santhana gopalam”?",
    "answerText": " Poonthanam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71883,
    "questionText": " Indian Lac Research Institute is located at?",
    "answerText": " Ranchi (Bihar)."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71884,
    "questionText": " Which is the first trade union in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " The Travancore Labour Association formed in 1922."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71885,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of An American Tragedy ?",
    "answerText": " Theodore Dreiser"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71886,
    "questionText": " Hardwar is on the bank of which River?",
    "answerText": " Ganges"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71887,
    "questionText": " MRI -Magnetic Resonance imaging was originally discovered independently in1946 by?",
    "answerText": " Felix Bloch and Purcell"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71888,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Waiting for Godot”?",
    "answerText": " Thomas Becket"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71889,
    "questionText": " Highest Road (World)?",
    "answerText": " Le Narba Road -Ladhak"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71890,
    "questionText": " The Great fire of London was in the year?",
    "answerText": 1666
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71891,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Satyartha Prakash?",
    "answerText": " Swami Dayananda Saraswathi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71892,
    "questionText": " Which sector will be the main contributor to the economy in developed country?",
    "answerText": " Service sector"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71893,
    "questionText": " The district in Kerala with no forest is?",
    "answerText": " Alappuzha"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71894,
    "questionText": " The Constitution of America was adopted in ?",
    "answerText": 1789
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71895,
    "questionText": " Who were the leaders of Guruvayur Sathyagraha ?",
    "answerText": " K. Kelappan and A.K. Gopalan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71896,
    "questionText": " Colour blindness also known as Daltonism is a genetic disorder and It is the inability to distinguish between red colour and ?",
    "answerText": " Green colour"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71897,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Dr. Zhivago”?",
    "answerText": " Boris Pasternak"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71898,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Aksharam”?",
    "answerText": " O.N.V Kurup"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71899,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of ‘Around the World in Eighty Days’ ?",
    "answerText": " Jules Verne"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71900,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Ramanan”?",
    "answerText": " Changampuzha Krishna Pilla"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71901,
    "questionText": " River in the Sea?",
    "answerText": " Gulf Stream"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71902,
    "questionText": " The writing of the Persians was Cunieform adopted from the ?",
    "answerText": " Mesopotamians"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71903,
    "questionText": " Who is regarded as the Father of Modem Kerala Police?",
    "answerText": " OM Bensly"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71904,
    "questionText": " Egyptian script was pictographic in nature. It was known as?",
    "answerText": " Hierogliphics"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71905,
    "questionText": " A ridiculing comedy is called?",
    "answerText": " Satire"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71906,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Memories of the Rationalist”?",
    "answerText": " Vasanth Sathe"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71907,
    "questionText": " 4 bits =?",
    "answerText": " 1Nibble"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71908,
    "questionText": " Which is the largest city in America?",
    "answerText": " New York"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71909,
    "questionText": " Ottawa is on the bank of which River?",
    "answerText": " Ottawa"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71910,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “The Seagully”?",
    "answerText": " Anton Chekov"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71911,
    "questionText": " Which ruler of Travancore started the first post office in 1852 in Alappuzha?",
    "answerText": " Uthram Thirunal Marthanda Varma"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71912,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Vinay Patrika ?",
    "answerText": " Tulsidas"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71913,
    "questionText": " Who is the creator of the famous character Tess?",
    "answerText": " Thomas Hardy"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71914,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Malgudi Days “?",
    "answerText": " R.K. Narayan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71915,
    "questionText": " Who is known as Man of Blood and Iron ?",
    "answerText": " Bismark"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71916,
    "questionText": " Longest Small Ship Canal?",
    "answerText": " Beloye (White Sea) Baltic Canal (CIS) 226 km long."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71917,
    "questionText": " Chalcolithic Age is known as ?",
    "answerText": " The Metal Age"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71918,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “My Childhood Days”?",
    "answerText": " Taslima Nasreen"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71919,
    "questionText": " The period in which The Industrial Revolution first started in England is?",
    "answerText": " The second half of the 18th century"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71920,
    "questionText": " Pookode lake is a famous tourist centre in?",
    "answerText": " Wayanad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71921,
    "questionText": " Ramavanna Kulasekhara shifted his capital from Mahodayapuram to?",
    "answerText": " Quilon"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71922,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of An American Dilemma?",
    "answerText": " Gunnar Myrdal"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71923,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Pravachakante Vazhi”?",
    "answerText": " O.V Vijayan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71924,
    "questionText": " The Peasants Revolt in England was in ?",
    "answerText": 1381
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71925,
    "questionText": " Pollination by Bat ?",
    "answerText": " Chiropterephily"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71926,
    "questionText": " Kumarakom tourist village is in?",
    "answerText": " Kottayam district"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71927,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Story of My Life ?",
    "answerText": " Moshe Dayan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71928,
    "questionText": " Hepatitis B causing virus is ?",
    "answerText": " Hepatitis B virus"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71929,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Shivaji- The Great Patriot”?",
    "answerText": " Lala Lajpat Rai"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71930,
    "questionText": " Which was the first Talkie Film in Malayalam?",
    "answerText": " Balan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71931,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of One Life ?",
    "answerText": " Christian Bernard"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71932,
    "questionText": " Which crop was called 'Yavana priya'?",
    "answerText": " Pepper "
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71933,
    "questionText": " The Currency of Papua New Guinea?",
    "answerText": " Kina"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71934,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “The Lion and the Jewel”?",
    "answerText": " Wole Soynika"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71935,
    "questionText": " Stock exchange Index of Hong Kong is?",
    "answerText": " Hang Seng"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71936,
    "questionText": " 2014ലെ മാതൃഭൂമി പുരസ്കാരം? ",
    "answerText": " സുഗതകുമാരി "
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71937,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of Vaccination (Small Pox)?",
    "answerText": " Edward Jenner"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71938,
    "questionText": " Growth and metabolic rate is the function of which hormone?",
    "answerText": " Thyroxin produced by Thyroid gland"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71939,
    "questionText": " Who shifted the capital of Travancore from Padmanabhapuram to?",
    "answerText": " Trivandrum. Dharma Raja"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71940,
    "questionText": " Who is the creator of the famous character “Zhivago”",
    "answerText": " Boris Pasternak"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71941,
    "questionText": " Who is the creator of the famous character Kim?",
    "answerText": " Rudyard Kipling"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71942,
    "questionText": " Where was the first Jewish Church established in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Kodungalloor"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71943,
    "questionText": " The Capital of Bolivia?",
    "answerText": " La Paz"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71944,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Summer in Kolkata “?",
    "answerText": " Madhavikutty (Kamala Surayya)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71945,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Kanthapura “?",
    "answerText": " Raja Rao"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71946,
    "questionText": " Amerigo Vespucci reached the South American coast in?",
    "answerText": 1499
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71947,
    "questionText": " ‘Damayanthi Talking to a Swan’ is a famous painting of?",
    "answerText": " Raja Ravi Varma"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71948,
    "questionText": " A Share trader who expects the price of share to fall is called a?",
    "answerText": " Bear"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71949,
    "questionText": " Low income and middle income countries are known as?",
    "answerText": " Developing Countries"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71950,
    "questionText": " Diphtheria and Tetanus vaccine was discovered by ?",
    "answerText": " Emil Adolf Von Belming and Shibasaburo Kitasato (1891)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71951,
    "questionText": " What is known as graveyard of RBC?",
    "answerText": " Spleen"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71952,
    "questionText": " Who translated Mahabharata, the epic in Sanskrit, into pure Malayalam, the first complete malayalam translation of the epic, within 874 days in 1887?",
    "answerText": " Kodungalloor Kunhikuttan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71953,
    "questionText": " The Capital of Sudan?",
    "answerText": " Khartoum"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71954,
    "questionText": " Who was the first to become Chief Minister after holding the position of Deputy Chief Minister?",
    "answerText": " R. Sankar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71955,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Swapnavasavdatta”?",
    "answerText": " Bhasa"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71956,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Beginning of the Beginning”?",
    "answerText": " Bhagwan Sri Rajneesh"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71957,
    "questionText": " Who is considered as the founder of the Persian Empire?",
    "answerText": " Cyrus"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71958,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Tryst with Destiny”?",
    "answerText": " S.Gopalan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71959,
    "questionText": " Which is the largest dam in the Bharathapuzha river?",
    "answerText": " Malampuzha dam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71960,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Imaging India?",
    "answerText": " Nandan Nilekani"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71961,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Uttar Ramcharita”?",
    "answerText": " Bhava Bhuti"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71962,
    "questionText": " Feudal System first emerged in ?",
    "answerText": " Europe"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71963,
    "questionText": " Which century is known as the' Age of Enlightenment'?",
    "answerText": " 18th century"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71964,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Whose responsibility”?",
    "answerText": " Pramilla H. Bhargava"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71965,
    "questionText": " Poverty and UnBritish Rule in India was written by ?",
    "answerText": " Dadabai Navoroji"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71966,
    "questionText": " Who is the creator of the famous characters “Chirutha; classipper”",
    "answerText": " Thakazhi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71967,
    "questionText": " First person to conquer Mount Everest?",
    "answerText": " Serpa Tenzing and Hillary"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71968,
    "questionText": " The scientific name of Earthworm is?",
    "answerText": " Pheretima Posthuma"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71969,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Iron Harvest”?",
    "answerText": " C.P.Surendran"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71970,
    "questionText": " Who is the inventor of Atomic Physics?",
    "answerText": " Ernest Rutherford"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71971,
    "questionText": " What is a form of stage drama in Japan?",
    "answerText": " Kabuki"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71972,
    "questionText": " Which civilization invented wheel and glassware?",
    "answerText": " The Mesopotamians"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71973,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of As I see?",
    "answerText": " Kiran Bedi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71974,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Gul-e-Naghma Raghupati ?",
    "answerText": " Sahai Firaq"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71975,
    "questionText": " ….is the market value of all products and services produced in one year by labour and property supplied by the-residents of a country?",
    "answerText": " Gross National Product"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71976,
    "questionText": " Muthanga wildlife sanctuary is located at?",
    "answerText": " Wayanad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71977,
    "questionText": " The Capital of Bermuda?",
    "answerText": " Hamilton"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71978,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Mrs.Warren’s Profession”?",
    "answerText": " G.B.Shaw"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71979,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Deserted Village”?",
    "answerText": " Oliver Goldsmith"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71980,
    "questionText": " Mahodayapuram is the old name of?",
    "answerText": " Kodungallur"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71981,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “India for a Billion Reasons”?",
    "answerText": " Amit Dasgupta"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71982,
    "questionText": " Quebec is on the bank of which River?",
    "answerText": " St.Lawrence"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71983,
    "questionText": " Which is the first biography in literature ?",
    "answerText": " Parallel Lives by Plutarch"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71984,
    "questionText": " Tradition ascribes the immediate origin of Kathakali to the Ramanattom developed by?",
    "answerText": " Kottarakara Thampuran"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71985,
    "questionText": " The number of chambers in the heart of a bird is ?",
    "answerText": " Four."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71986,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “All's Well that Ends Well”?",
    "answerText": " Shakespeare"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71987,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of Universe Around Us ?",
    "answerText": " James Jeans"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71988,
    "questionText": " Kunjan Nambiar and Unnayi Warrier were the famous poets in the court of ?",
    "answerText": " Dharmaraja."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71989,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “Years of the Upheaval”?",
    "answerText": " Henry Kissinger"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71990,
    "questionText": " ‘Lady lost in Thought’ is a famous painting of?",
    "answerText": " Raja Ravi Varma"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71991,
    "questionText": " The Currency of Malaysia?",
    "answerText": " Malaysian Dollar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71992,
    "questionText": " On the banks of which river The Eiffel Tower is situated?",
    "answerText": " Seine in Paris"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71993,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of “ Distant Neighbours”?",
    "answerText": " Kuldip Nayar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71994,
    "questionText": " Driest Place?",
    "answerText": " Death Valley (California)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71995,
    "questionText": " Bisley is associated with which Sport?",
    "answerText": " Shooting"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71996,
    "questionText": " The Capital of Greece?",
    "answerText": " Athens"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71997,
    "questionText": " Insectivorous plants obtain nitrogen from ?",
    "answerText": " animal bodies."
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71998,
    "questionText": " The inhabitance of England in the Neolithic Age were known as ?",
    "answerText": " Iberians"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 71999,
    "questionText": " Who is known as Kerala Panini?",
    "answerText": " AR Raja Raja Varma"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 72000,
    "questionText": " The scientific name of Pig is?",
    "answerText": " Sus scrofa"
  }
]